--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
影片压制: 牛仔　字幕调校：铭瑄　招募Q号: 76846146
别擦  孩子
No, son. Never.
血要留在刀刃上
The blood stays on the blade.
总有一天你会明白的
One day you'll understand.
关于往事我只剩一半记忆
Some of it I half remember.
其余的
And the rest
其余的从梦里得来
The rest I took from dreams.
圣米歇尔  总领天使在战斗中保佑我们
St. Michael, the archangel, defend us in battle.
是我们的守护神
Be our protector against the snares
帮助我们对抗魔鬼的邪恶和陷阱
and the wickedness of the devil.
好了  孩子  那是谁?
Now, son, who's that?
- 圣米歇尔  - 上面是谁?
- St. Michael. - Who is it?
- 圣米歇尔  - 他的使命?
- St. Michael! - And what did he do?
他把撒旦逐出天堂
He cast Satan out of paradise.
好孩子
Good boy.
主将圣灵的力量注入你们的脊梁
May God put the steel of the Holy Spirit in your spine
将圣母的爱放入你们的心中
and the love of the Blessed Virgin in your heart.
- 哥们  - 约翰尼
- Hey, boyo! - Johnny.
- 哪几方交战?  - 本地帮对死兔帮
- What's the battle? -  Natives against the Dead Rabbits.
- 你是哪边的?  - 你说呢?当然是死兔帮
-  Which are you? -  What do you think? Dead Rabbits.
蒙克
Well, well, Monk.
你是否随我们去?
Are you with us or not?
最后一次了  瓦伦如果开价合理我就去
For the last time, Vallon, I'm with you if the money is right.
每条刀痕10元
I'll give you 10 per notch.
- 10元?  - 我说话算数
- Ten? - You have my word.
- 每条刀痕10元?  - 新的才算数
- Ten per notch? - Per new notch.
我为你们效力
Then I'm your man.
就这么些人?牧师?  教皇陛下的新人马?
Is this it, Priest? The pope's new army?
几条莽汉和贱民?
A few crusty bitches and a handful of ragtags?
比尔  你说过这是勇者之战
Now, now, Bill, you swore this was a battle between warriors
可不是泼妇骂街
not a bunch of Miss Nancys.
所以我只把战士带来了
So warriors is what I brought.
奥康尔卫士帮
The O'Connell Guard.
搅屎棍帮
The Plug Uglies.
屁帘帮
The Shirt Tails.
齐切斯特帮
The Chichesters.
四十大盗帮
The forty Thieves.
我发出挑战
On my challenge
依据决斗的老规矩
by the ancient laws of combat, we have met at this chosen ground
我们选择在此决斗
to settle, for good and all
以决定哪方永久持有五点区的控制权
who holds sway over the Five Points:
决定这块乐土是归于土生土长的地头蛇
Us Natives, born right-wise to this fine land
还是沦落于外国蛮子控制之下
or the foreign hordes defiling it.
依据决斗的老规矩  我接受所谓本地帮的挑战
By the ancient laws of combat, I accept the challenge of the so-called Natives.
你们常陷我们于水火之中
You plague our people at every turn.
从今天起  你们无法再欺凌我们
But from this day out, you shall plague us no more.
我们要让大家知道  想把我们推出这片土地的手
For let it be known that the hand that tries to strike us from this land
理应一刀砍去
shall be swiftly cut down.
让基督教徒藉主的指引
Then may the Christian Lord guide my hand
对抗你们这帮天主教徒
against your Roman popery!
准备迎纳真正的主吧
Prepare to receive the true Lord!
牧师
Priest!
看着我
Look to me.
谁倒在我的刀下?
Who is this under my knife?
爸爸  起来  起来
Father, get up. Get up!
你在哪?  你在哪?
Where are you? Where are you?
我的孩子
Oh, my son.
别把脸转过去
Don't never look away.
很快就结束了  牧师
Soon be over, Priest.
了结我吧
Finish it.
你在地府也许用得到这个
You may need this across the river.
可以割下鼻子耳朵作为今天的战利品
Ears and noses will be the trophies of the day.
但此人谁也不许碰
But no hand shall touch him!
谁也不许碰他
No hand shall touch him!
他死得
He'll cross over whole
有尊严
in honor.
先让我拿走他欠我的钱
Not before I get what's owed.
别动
No!
很公平  虽然不是很得体  但很公平
It's fair. A touch indelicate, but fair.
我深表同情
My sympathies.
怎么处理这小子?
What will we do with the boy?
看着我
Look at me.
把他交给警察
Give him to the law.
他能受到好的教育
See he gets a good education.
小子  和你爸爸道别吧
Okay, boy, say goodbye to your father.
- 抓住他  - 抓住他
- Get him! - Get him!
别让他跑了
Don't let him get away.
快点  来这
Hurry, come in here!
他跑到下面去了
He's going downstairs.
过来  小子
Come here, boy.
- 你跑不了了  小子  - 他在这  抓住他
- You're going to Hellgate, son. - There he is. Get him.
- 牧师瓦伦死的光荣  - 放开我
-  Priest Vallon died a noble death   -  Let go of me!
他的死兔帮也寿终正寝了
but his Dead Rabbits is done and outlawed!
从今往后谁也不许提到这些名字
Let no one even speak their name from this time on.
纽约市
在这个地方  你已从男孩成长为男人
In this place, you have grown from a boy into a man.
16年后
要摒弃你过去种种罪孽  无仁  无义
Put to death the earthly things in you: Immorality, impurity
冲动  报复欲
passion, vengeance.
主已经宽恕了你
The Lord has forgiven you.
你也必须宽恕自己
You also must forgive.
你要前往一个因暴力争斗而四分五裂的地区(罪人之路艰难困苦)
You go forth to a country torn apart by civil strife.
谢谢您  牧师
Thank you, Reverend.
为未竟之事业尽一份力
Lend your hand to the work that yet remains
希望纷争可以结束
that this war may end
给人类带来巨大灾难的奴隶制度
and the plague of slavery that brought this conflagration
在地球上消失无踪
down upon us vanish forever from the earth.
南北战争的第二年
In the second year of the Civil War
正是爱尔兰人上街游行的时候
when the Irish Brigade marched in the streets
纽约是个族裔众多
New York was a city full of tribes
军官林立  贫富纷杂的都市
war chiefs, rich and poor.
- 打倒林肯  - 林肯想把所有白人变成奴隶
- Down with Lincoln! -  Lincoln will make all white men slaves.
这真算不上是一个城市
It wasn 't a city really.
更像是一个大熔炉  也许某天能融会锻造出一个城市来
It was more a furnace where a city someday might be forged.
就是这样  小伙子们
That's the spirit, boys.
- 快为你们的黑鬼朋友送命去吧  - 打倒废奴者
-  Go off and die for your blackie friends. -  Down with the abolitionists!
我们得找机会选出一个更强有力的人物来对抗林肯
We shoule run a better man against Lincoln when we had the chance.
纽约要脱离联邦
New York should secede from the Union!
他想尽力表明我们和黑鬼们没区别?
They trying to say we're no different than niggers?
- 当然有区别  - 晚上好  兄弟
- You ain't. - Good evening, brother.
- 上帝拯救联邦  这就是联邦
- Praise the Union. -  The Union forever!
滚回非洲去  黑鬼
Go back to Africa, nigger!
- 滚回非洲去  - 放开他  我们自由了
- Go back to Africa! - Leave him alone. We're free.
最引起公愤的是新征兵法
The angriest talk was of the new Conscription Act
联邦史上头号征兵法
the first draft in Union history.
参军吧  小伙子  一天三餐  待遇优厚
Join the Army, lads. Three square meals a day and good pay in your pocket.
爱尔兰人来的时候  这个城市一片狂热
When the Irish came, the city was in a fever.
自本土发生大饥荒以来  爱尔兰人乘船如潮水般涌至
Since the time of the great famine, they'd come streaming off the boats.
他们受到了热烈的欢迎
And they got a right warm welcome.
- 滚回家去  爱尔兰傻瓜  - 记住了  死鬼爱尔兰人
- Go back to Ireland, you dumb micks! - Remember that, you Irish gyps!
滚回船上去
Get back on the boat, Paddy!
我来自船程仅两小时的地狱门
I only came two hours downriver from Hellgate.
可别人把我当成外来移民
But they all took me for an immigrant.
这也正常  纽约本地就有上千种口音
Why not? There were a thousand different accents in New York.
我和移民也没不同
And to the Natives, you see, we was all the same.
欢迎来到美国  孩子  漫长艰巨的旅途结束了
Welcome to America, son. Your long, arduous journey is over.
- 滚回你的国家去  - 投坦慕尼一票
- Go back to your own country! - Vote Tammany!
纽约对威廉.特威德既爱且恨
New York loved William Tweed and hated him.
我们这些想作小偷的人  忍不住对他肃然起敬
And those of us trying to be thieves, well, we couldn 't help but admire him.
卡丁先生  先生们  多谢光临  非常荣幸
Mr. Cutting, gentlemen, thank you for coming. It's an honor.
特威德先生
Mr. Tweed.
先生  请别这样
Sir, please. Excuse me.
- 你吓着它们了  - 那怎么了?
- I think you're frightening them. - So?
别介意  他以前是爱尔兰人
Don't mind him. He used to be an Irishman.
五点区
Ah, the Five Points.
杀手巷  碎砖大楼  地狱门
Murderers' Alley. Brickbat Mansion. The Gates of Hell.
就是这个简陋的地方  看看这个可怜的孩子的脸
Here in this vile place. Look upon the face of this poor child.
她居住的环境肮脏潦倒
She lives in squalor
就在我后面这个破败凄凉的狗窝里
in this godforsaken den of vice and misery behind me.
改良派年年来
Every year the reformers came.
五点区却越来越糟
Every year the Points got worse
仿佛它天生不爱干净(五点区教会)
as if it liked being dirty.
- 我要去哪里?  - 走!  牧师让你离开这里
- Where am I going to go? -  The Reverend wants you out of here.
你不能这么作
You can't do this!
你这条臭蛆
to which these miserable creatures have fallen.
比尔也许你知道   我每天都到码头去
You may or may not know, Bill, that every day I go to the waterfront
为刚到埠的爱尔兰人奉上热汤
with hot soup for the Irish as they come ashore.
这是打好政治基础的一部分
It's part of building a political base.
我在那留意到你了你应该也见到我了
I've noticed you there. You may have noticed me.
确实如此  你肆意羞辱
Indeed I have. Throwing torrents of pavers and withering abuse
- 每个下船的人  - 如果只有我有枪
- on everyone stepping off those boats. -  If only I had the guns
那帮家伙一踏上美国土地我就宰了他们
I'd shoot each and every one of them before they set foot on American soil.
墨贝理街
Mulberry Street
沃什区
and Worth.
十字区橘子区
Cross and Orange and Little Water.
五点的每个区都是一根手指
Each of the Five Points is a finger.
我一握紧手  它就变成了拳头
When I close my hand, it becomes a fist.
只要我愿意  我就把拳头对着你
And any time that I wish, I can turn it against you.
我明白  但我们谈的是两回事
I know, but we're talking about different things.
我谈的是公民义务  我们对大众应负的责任
I'm talking about civic duty, responsibilities we owe to the people.
学校、医院、下水道、公用设施
Schools and hospitals, sewers and utilities.
道路建设、修整及清洁
Street construction, repairs and sweeping.
营业执照  酒吧执照
Business licenses, saloon licenses
圣米歇尔  总领天使  在作战中保佑我们
St. Michael, the archangel, defend us in battle.
是我们的守护神帮助我们对抗魔鬼
Be our protector against the snares and the wickedness of the devil.
街车  轮渡  垃圾处理
Street cars, ferries, rubbish disposal.
以及这座城市创造财富的能力  比尔
There's a power of money to be made in this city, Bill.
有你的帮助  应该让人们明白
With your help, the people must be made to understand
这一切必须在我称之为'坦慕尼大家庭'之中
that all these things are best kept within the Tammany family
才能运作的最好
which is why I'm proposing an alliance
所以我才找你商谈我们两大团体之间的结盟
between our two great organizations.
- 你说的都是力气活  - 没错  加强力量正是我们的精神
- You're talking about muscle work. -  That too. Muscle to match our spirit.
你手里有警察  可以让他们去做
You own the crushers. Get them to do it.
警察?  不行!
The police? Oh, no. Jesus, no!
法律的形象必须得维护
The appearance of the law must be upheld
法将不法的时候更得维护
especially while it's being broken.
赐予我力量以完成我的使命
Give me the strength for what I must do.
你是谁?
Who are you?
- 嘿 - 别动
- Hey! - No!
我问你  你是谁?  你在这里做什么?
I said, who are you? What are you doing here?
我只是喜欢来这里  这这样
I just like it down here is all.
搜搜他的身  吉米
See what's in his pockets, Jimmy.
- 听着  伙计们  我真的不想打架  - 不想打架?
- Look, boys, I really don't want a fight. - Don't want a fight?
别担心  小子  不会打架的
Don't worry, son, ain't gonna be much a fight.
别杀我
Don't kill me.
你从哪找到这东西的?
Where'd you get that?
我说了不想打架的
I told you I didn't want a fight!
为什么?  看你身手多好啊
Why not? Look how good you done.
- 你是牧师的儿子吗?  - 你离我远点  明白吗?
- You're the Priest's son, aren't you? - You, get away from me, understand?
你不记得我了?  我就是那个想救你命的人
You don't remember me, do you? I's the one tried to help you.
- 什么?  - 我就是那个想救你命的人
- What? - I's the one tried to help you
在本地帮抓你的时候
when the Natives took you.
- 是你吗?  - 是的  我以为你被杀了
- Oh, that was you? - Yeah. I thought you was killed.
他们只是把我关起来了
They just locked me up, you know that?
这么久?
This long?
可我总是想方设法逃跑  他们就把我多关了些日子
Well, I kept trying to escape, you know. They add on time for that.
你回来做什么?
So, what are you doing back here?
我想念这个地方
I guess I missed the place.
鲍瑞街的混小子
Bowery Boys.
给我回来
Get back here!
五点区  天堂广场
The Five Points, Paradise Square.
到了晚上街道总是生机勃勃
The streets here are always lively of an evening.
现在都有些什么帮派?
Who are the gangs around now?
有'黎明小子'和'沼泽探子'
The Daybreak Boys and the Swamp Angels.
他们在河上以抢劫船只谋生
They work the river, looting ships.
上海水手青蛙帮在血天使区一带活动
The frog Hollows shanghai sailors by the Bloody Angle.
'屁帘帮'一度强盛  现在成为'花花公子帮'一部分
The Shirt Tails was rough, but they've become a bunch of dandies
在杀手街盘踞  穿得像中国人
Iolling around Murderers' Alley, looking like Chinamen.
地狱猫麦姬 自己开了个酒吧
Hell-Cat Maggie, she tried to open her own grog shop.
可惜酒全被她自己喝完了  结果被人赶到大街上
She drunk her own liquor and got throwed on the street.
- 真漂亮  - 现从事各种非法勾当
- Beautiful. - Now she's on the lay for anything.
还有搅屎棍帮  不知道从哪个国家的角落来的
The Plug Uglies are from deep in the old country.
有自己的语言
Got their own language no one understands.
他们喜欢找警察的茬  还有破烂街的'夜行人帮'
They love to fight the cops. The Night Walkers of Ragpicker's Row.
喜欢鬼鬼祟祟跟在人后面把人掐死
They work on their backs and kill with their hands.
他们如此卑鄙  只有搅屎棍帮愿意与他们搭腔  谁也听不懂
They're so scurvy only the Plug Uglies talk to them. But who understands them?
还有'屠场屠夫'和'百老汇舞者'
The Slaughter Housers and the Broadway Twisters.
都是一群赌棍  以及四十小盗
They're a fine bunch of bingo boys. And the Little forty Thieves.
我曾和他们厮混过一段
I used to run with them
直到他们被本德里克收并
till they got took over by Bendrick the Cockroach.
本德里克是个混蛋兼小人
Bendrick carries a germ.
他订了个规矩  谁敢离开帮派就给谁放血
If you try to leave the gang, he hacks up blood on you.
可他们只会在街头巷尾诅咒英国
The lime-juicers are nothing but a bunch of rapacious grab- ups.
'真蓝美国人'自称帮派
The True Blue Americans say they're a gang
可他们只会在街头巷尾诅咒英国
but all they do is stand on corners damning England.
如果你相信英国佬任何一句话  你就是个傻瓜
If you believe one word the British say, you're a fool.
有没有人接手'死兔帮'?
Do any of them got the sand of the Dead Rabbits?
你不能提这个名字
You don't say that name.
这个名字已经死去  和你的    这些都被取缔了
That name died with your   They been outlawed.
我被关押期间  中国佬告诉我
In the blockhouse, the Chinks told me
本地帮每年都在庆祝胜利  是不是真的?
that the Natives celebrate their victory every year. Is that true?
确实如此  算是件大事
Aye, that they do. It's quite the affair.
屠夫亲自邀请过你  你不去
The Butcher himself's got to invite you, or you don't go.
你怎么走的路  约翰尼
Look where you're going, Johnny.
你看起来像只呆头鹅
You look stunned and poorly, sir.
好一对演说家
Quite a pair of conversationists, aren't you?
不对  我们都是思想家
Maybe not, but we're deep thinkers.
先生们  我留你们继续享受上帝的恩惠和关怀
Well, gentlemen, I leave you in the grace and favor of the Lord.
珍妮  最棒的妙手空空
Jenny, the finest bludget in all the Points.
我觉得她像个美艳的算命小姐
She is a prim-looking stargazer.
你最好检查一下口袋
But I'd check my pockets if I was you
我相信她把你的表偷走了
because I do believe she lifted your timepiece.
我让她拿的
Well, I let her take it.
我的东西随便让她拿
I let her take things all the time.
- 是吗?  - 是的
- Is that right? - Yeah.
我们总是希望在五点区能来点火灾
We always liked a good fire in the Points.
通常可以顺手牵羊  如果警察来了  还有好戏可看
You could pick up a little swag. And if the cops came, you really got a show.
由市属警察迎战都会警察
The Municipal Police fought the Metropolitan Police.
都会警察则迎战街头黑帮
The Metropolitan Police, they fought the street gangs.
快点  伙计们  要赶在'黑杰克'之前
Hurry up, men, before the Black Joke get there!
还有37个业余消防队  也彼此缠斗不休
There were 37 amateur fire brigades, and they all fought each other.
黑杰克正在路上  特威德  他们会把你们打惨的
The Black Joke are on their way, Tweed, and they'll beat the shite out of you.
好了  小伙子们
Okay, boys, get the hose out!
黑杰克来了
It's the Black Joke!
去挡住他们  小伙子们
Go get them, boys!
给他们点颜色瞧瞧
Give those Bowery Boys hell!
- 快点  别被人全拿走了  - 滚出去  你们这帮浑蛋
- Quick, before there's nothing left. - Go back to the Bowery, you bums!
快制止他们  天啊他们把东西全拿跑了
Stop them. For God's sake, they're taking everything!
以后再遇到麻烦夫人  先找坦慕尼
In your next time of trouble, call on Tammany first.
可还为时未晚  你们还可以挽救我的房子
But it's not too late. You can still save my house.
走吧
Let's go.
你说你饿了
I thought you said you was hungry.
尽可能多拿些!  快走吧!
Grab what you can, Johnny. Let's get out of here.
需要我告诉你这座房子会烧会灰吗?
May I point out that this building is burning to ashes?
需要我告诉你这里是属于阿梅里克斯消防队管辖的区域
May I point out this area is the province of my own Americus fire Brigade
你们的范围仅限于鲍瑞吗?
and that you lot belong only in the Bowery?
需要我告诉你你们已经处于下风  劣势
May I point out that you're outmanned, outmaneuvered
并且快要被打败了吗?
and, in a moment, outfought?
是吗?
Am I?
黑杰克在这里让他们别挡道
There's the Black Joke! Let's take them on the cobbles.
去饱揍他们一顿
Go spill some claret, boys. Go on, Shorty, have a nice muss.
为屠夫比尔开道
Clear the way for Bill the Butcher.
好吧  小伙子们  动手吧
Okay, boys, to work.
到底要干什么?  屋里值钱的东西差不多全烧光了
What's the point? The fire's near burned anything of value inside.
小伙子们  别管这幢了  去旁边那幢
Boys, forget that one. Next building over.
不能让火蔓延开  那房子的东西随便拿
Mustn't let it spread. Take what you want from that one.
你们干什么?
What are you doing?
这房子没问题啊  这是我的房子
There's nothing wrong with this one. This is my house.
- 约翰尼  - 救命
- Johnny! - Help!
-  Johnny! - Help!
救命  救命
Help! Help!
救命
Help!
快走  快走  约翰尼  起来
Come on. Come on, Johnny, get up.
别拿了
Leave that!
你们俩快走开
You two, out of the way!
他叫阿姆斯特丹
His name's Amsterdam.
- 货色如何?  - 还行
-  How's the beak? -  Ain't so bad.
你  有东西就交出来  要不就出去
You. You got anything, you give it up or you get out.
就这些?
Is that it?
就这些
That's it.
好了  跟你说规矩  交来这的所有东西  由我们变卖
Right. Here's the rake. Everything comes here. We fence it.
约翰尼把贡金交给本地帮  然后我们分配所得
Johnny takes our tribute to the Natives, and we chop up the winnings
根据每个人在帮中的地位
each to his equal portion, amongst the gang.
这规矩你满意吗?地狱门?
Does that meet with your approval, Hellgate?
我满意吗?
My approval?
什么意思?杰克你不会自己动脑子吗?
What's the matter, Jack Sprat? Can't think for yourself?
- 我撕烂你的喉咙  - 来呀
- I'll slit your fucking throat! - Hey, come on!
你们分赃之前该先和我算算帐
You boys will settle with me before settling with each other.
我来要我的份子钱
I come for my due and proper.
收获不小啊
Well, this ain't a bad haul.
别人问我这个关于国家前景我怎么说吗?
When folks start in to saying to where the country is going to hell
我说  '到五点区去观摩那些棒小伙多么辛勤工作就知道了'
I always tell them, "You just look at all the hard work..our fine young lads is doing down in the Five Points."
这东西送穆拉尼夫人正合适
Oh, yeah. Now this is just the thing for Mrs. Mulraney.
好的 哈皮·杰克 给我们留点东西孝敬屠夫比尔
All right there, Happy Jack, leave us something  to quarter to Bill the Butcher, eh?
行吗?
Would you?
这音乐我不喜欢
Not my favorite tune.
谢了  小伙子们
Thank you, boys.
你们没事了
You keep out of trouble now.
每年本地帮一次次地庆祝我父亲的死
Every year the Natives celebrated the killing of my father all over again
地点就在莫特街中国麻将馆
at Sparrow's Chinese Pagoda in Mott Street.
中国人比我们还恨本地帮
The Chinks hated the Natives worse than we did.
当鼓声响起屠夫会喝下一杯火酒
The drum rolls, and the Butcher drinks a glass of fire.
要杀死一位国王
When you kill a king
你不该在黑暗中狙杀他
you don 't stab him in the dark.
而要在众目睽睽之下杀了他
You kill him where the whole court can watch him die.
有火吗?
Hey, you got any timber?
- 麦琪  左耳还是右耳?  - 快给我们酒喝 你这白痴
- Hey, Maggie. Right ear or left ear? - Give us a drink, you idiot.
自己动手吧
Help yourself.
- 最后押注!  - 为健康干杯
- Final bets! - To health.
快下注吧  最后2分钟
Place your bets. Betting closes in two minutes.
快下注吧
Place your bets.
先生们  比赛要开始了
Gentlemen, the match is due to commence.
数目是三分钟内吃掉25只老鼠
The count to beat is 25 rodents in three minutes.
鼠狗大战
Towser against the vermin.
- 大家满意吗?  - 50
- Are the enumerators satisfied? - Fifty!
- 好的  - 放出来吧
- Yes! - Let them go!
- 你要干什么  小伙子?  - 我来给比尔进贡
- Where you going, boy? - I'm here to pay tribute to Bill.
是吗?  把钱给我  我交给他
Are you now? Give it to me. I'll give it to him.
不用了  多谢  还是我自己来吧
No, thanks. I'll give it to him myself.
你是想留着你的牙齿还是钱?
What do you want to keep, the money or your teeth?
约翰
John.
欢迎
Welcome.
我和我的朋友的  先生
From me and me lads, sir.
你的朋友?  他是哪来的?
Mate of yours? Where's he from?
他不是本地人  先生
Oh, he's not from here, sir.
你
You.
别再走近了
That's close enough.
你朋友没有看着我的眼睛  这可不是很有礼貌的行为
Your friend can't look me in the eye. That's not an admirable characteristic.
没人能看着你的眼睛  比尔  尤其是你玩牌的时候
No one can look you in the eye, Bill. Not when you're playing cards.
这是惠斯特  绅士的游戏  下注该有个绅士的样子
This is whist. It's a gentleman's game. Make a gentleman's bet.
- 我下得够大了  比尔  - 不够大
- I'm betting large, Bill. - That ain't large.
拜托别再嚷嚷了  哈威
Please, don't make that noise again, Harvey.
我喜欢对财富极度渴望的人
I like a man who's willing to burn for his swag.
你水性好吗?  走近点
How do you fare on water? Come closer.
近点  约翰  我不会咬人的 再近点
Close, John. I ain't gonna bite. Close.
有一艘葡萄牙船停靠在港口  有三个星期的检疫期
There's a Portuguese ship lying low in the harbor, quarantined three weeks.
趁黎明小子洗劫前下手
Get there before the Daybreak Boys strip her
可能我们还得仔细商量一下
maybe you and me will talk more.
- 没问题  先生  - 好样的
- Consider it done, sir. - Good boy.
你  叫什么名字?  你叫什么名字?
And you, whatever your name is   What is your name?
- 阿姆斯特丹  先生  - 阿姆斯特丹  那我就叫纽约
- Amsterdam, sir. - Amsterdam. I'm New York.
注：纽约前名Nieuw Amsterdam新阿姆斯特丹
下次来别再一毛不拔了
Don't you never come in here empty-handed again.
你得有所付出  讨讨我手下欢心
You gotta pay for the pleasure of my company.
带上他一起行动  约翰
Take him for a boat ride, John.
也许他能再救你一命
Who knows, but he might save your life again.
被黎明小子抓到  会割断我们的喉咙
The Daybreak Boys catch us, they'll slit our throats.
你要不闭嘴我就割断你的喉咙
I'll do it myself in a minute if you don't keep quiet.
我不喜欢入夜后的港口
I never liked the harbor after dark.
每天晚上都有士兵的尸体运来
And now each night they brung ashore the bodies of the soldiers.
许多母亲甚至不知道儿子战死在何方
Many mothers have not even the solace
不知道儿子战死在何方
of knowing where their sons have fallen.
安提塔姆战役中我失去了长子
I lost my own eldest at Antietam.
我和他母亲至今无法找回遗体
His mother and I were unable to recover his remains.
-那是幅悲惨的景象  -战争不能永远持续下去
- It was a mournful sight. - The war can't last forever.
可我们有自己的事要作
But we had business of our own.
黎明小子已经来过了  洗劫一空  回去吧
The Daybreak Boys have been here, and there's nothing left. Let's go back.
怎么回事
What the hell?
吉米  趴下
Jimmy, get down!
天啊  一定会把警察引来
Jesus, than bring the harbor cops for sure. Fuck off.
去看看吧
Let's take a look.
天啊  他们杀得鸡犬不留
Jesus, they killed everybody.
除了一堆死螃蟹什么都没剩下
There's nothing here but a bunch of dead sea-crabs.
快  走吧
Come on, let's go.
- 开船  - 别走  等等阿姆斯特丹
- Shove off. -  No, wait for Amsterdam.
阿姆斯特丹在哪?
Where's Amsterdam?
- 笨蛋  截住他  - 你在干什么?!
- No, you damn fool, take him! - What in the hell for?!
看看我的货  不少于15美金
Look in my glims. I said no less than 15.
- 新鲜吗  - 最多4小时
- Is this fresh? - Four hours most.
非常感谢  先生们
Much obliged, gents.
那是什么词?
What's that word?
- 意思是拿尸体  - 不是问意思
- It means body snatchers. - I didn't ask the meaning.
我问是个什么词
I asked the word.
盗尸者
Ghoul.
盗尸者?  好词
Ghoul? That's a good word.
"盗尸帮杀人  五点区最新暴行"
"Ghoul Gang Slaughters. A fresh Outrage in the Five Points."
- 这标题你应该感到自豪  - 多谢
- That's a notice you can be proud of. - Thank you.
没出息  这么对待尸体
A low thing, to do that to a body. Low.
为什么?  他们原本会空手而归
Why? They could have left that ship with nothing.
可结果他们上了《警察宪报》 一份定期刊物
Instead they made The Police Gazette, a periodical of note.
尸体应该埋在地下
A body's supposed to stay beneath the earth
穿着木衣直到重生
wearing a wooden coat until the Resurrection.
这俩人和你一样都是爱尔兰人的后代
These two are a pair of sons of Irish bitches, same as you.
别再搞他们了
It don't seem to bother them none.
也许他们和你的是非观念不同吧
But then maybe they don't share your religious scruples.
也许他们只是一对'费德兰奔'
Maybe they're just a couple of fidlam Bens.
Fidlam bens：黑话  什么都偷的贼
叫我什么的都有  可从没人叫我
I've been called a lot of things, mister, but I ain't never been called
- 费德兰奔  - 费德兰奔  没事
- Fidlam Bens. - Fidlam Bens. Right.
如果我知道确切意思  我可能会反击
Well, if I knew what in the hell that meant, I'd be inclined to take offense.
费德兰奔就是什么都偷的人  不论死活
A fidlam Bens is a fellow who steals anything, dead or alive
太没出息以至无法建立任何形象
because he's too low to work up a decent lay for himself.
小心点  屠夫  小心点
Count that careful, Bill. Count that careful.
- 我告诉你他们就给了这么多  - 小毛贼
- I'm telling you, that's all there is   - Now, chiseler
你说我们是小毛贼  这个词我明白  你知道吗?
If you'd said "chiseler," now there's a word I understand. You know?
- 你是这么叫我们吗?  - 我能想出一大堆名词称呼你们
- Now, is that what you're calling us? - I can think of many things to call you.
如果我问你是否称我们为'小毛贼'?
Right. But I asked if you was calling us chiselers.
是又如何?
Supposing I am?
那局面就不好收拾了
Well, then we got business.
来吧
That we do.
- 打起来了 - 两块押麦格罗恩
- A fight! There's a fight! - Two bucks on McGloin.
- 四块押小伙子  - 四块押小伙子
- Four bits on the kid. - Five bits on the kid.
五块押阿姆斯特丹!
I got two on Amsterdam.
上啊  麦格罗恩他不过是个小毛头
Come on, McGloin, he's just a kid.
押回阿姆斯特丹四块
Four bits to back Amsterdam.
小心他的左拳  麦格罗恩
Watch his left, McGloin. Watch his left.
- 行了  够了  够了  - 你还有什么可说的?
- All right, l do. l do. - Anything to say now, huh?!
行了  拉开他吧
OK, for chrissake. Drag him off.
- 够了  小子  你赢了  - 行了  小子  你赢了  别犯傻了
- That's enough, kid. - You got him. Come on, kid, you won.
麦格罗恩 他是个孩子
McGloin. He's a kid too, McGloin.
你太老了  麦格罗恩
You're getting too old for it, McGloin.
麦格罗恩  没鼻子耳朵的脑袋看起来是什么样的?
McGloin, how would that head look without the ears and the nose on it?
这种脑袋你最好别碰  比尔
You'd better leave that head alone, Bill.
我要把那脑袋的鼻子耳朵削掉
I think I'm gonna trim the ears and the beak off of that head.
用这脑袋做碗好汤
Make a nice pot of soup of that head.
有比这脑袋好味的脑袋  比尔
You could find a tastier head than that, Bill.
没爱尔兰炖肉我根本没胃口
I ain't got the stomach for no Irish stew.
大名鼎鼎的麦格罗恩差点成了个后生的手下败将
The mighty McGloin almost fishhooked by a sprat.
第七天上帝休息  在休息前
On the seventh day, the Lord rested, but before that he did
他蹲在英格兰旁边 拉出来的东西  就是爱尔兰
he squatted over the side of England, and what came out of him was Ireland.
- 没有冒犯你的意思  - 没关系  先生  我是在这长大的
- No offense, son. - Oh, none taken, sir. I grew up here.
关于爱尔兰的一切我都是在孤儿院听别人说的
All I ever knew of Ireland was in the talk of the others at the orphan asylum.
你的祖先产在那个粪便岛的那个部位?
In which part of that excrementitious isle were your forebears spawned?
我听说是克立  可从孤儿院起我就无法从口音证实这点了
I've been told Kerry, but I lost proof of it in my language at the asylum.
我也在相似的环境中长大
I was raised in a very similar establishment myself.
你看到属于我的东西都是某阶段的产物
Now everything you see belongs to me, to one degree or another.
天堂广场的乞丐  报童和小贼
The beggars and newsboys and quick thieves here in Paradise.
有钱的海员和低级酒吧  码头边劣质威士忌
The sailor dives and gin mills and blind tigers on the waterfront.
盎格鲁人  双性人和中国人
The anglers and amusers, the she- hes and the Chinks.
每个人都欠我钱  每个人都要付我钱
Everybody owes, everybody pays
只有如此才能逆流而上  成长起来
because that's how you stand up against the rising of the tide.
- 我说的对吗?  - 没错  比尔
- Is that right, boys? - Yeah, Bill. That's right.
加入我们的行列  为国效力
Enlist. Join up. Serve your country.
响应征兵法的号召
Come on in out of the draft, boys.
自告奋勇者可获50美元奖赏
Volunteer and get your $50 bonus.
我们需要30000名自愿者  我们准备支付每位自愿者677美元
We need 30,000 volunteers, and we're prepared to pay $677 per volunteer.
- 请看看这个  - 谢谢
- Please read this. Thank you. - Thanks.
你要拿一张来填吗?
Would you like to take one of these to fill out?
一日管三餐  一日管三餐
Three square meals a day. Three square meals a day.
年轻人  应征入伍报效国家
Young man, enlist and serve your country.
一日管三餐  先生
Three square meals a day, gentlemen.
如果有兴趣  建议你看一下这个再决定是否应征
If you're interested, read this and consider joining.
走到哪里人们都在谈论征兵
Everywhere you went people talked about the draft.
支付300美元可免于应征
Now, you could buy your way out for $300
可谁有300美元呢?
but who had $300?
对我们来说和三百万也没区别
For us it might as well have been 3 million.
对于征兵人员  他们害怕黑帮会找上我们
The recruiters? They was too scared of the gangs to come after us.
而且  我们从没想过战争会打到纽约
Besides, we never dreamt the war would ever touch New York.
早晨好  先生
Good morning, sir.
是你!
You!
你可别撞上我
Don't you run into me.
你知道了
Fair enough.
我说了别撞我
I said, don't run into me!
对不起
Well, sorry.
- 没丢东西吧?  - 好像没有
- Everything in place? - It seems so.
那我就留你继续享受上帝的恩惠和关怀
Well, then I leave you in the grace and favor of the Lord.
- 多谢  - 好了
- Thank you. - That's right.
这个死丫头
Oh, the dirty mab!
不
Oh, no.
- 对不起- 我来
- I'm sorry. - Allow me.
- 多谢你的好意  先生  - 乐意效劳
- Thank you kindly, sir. - Oh, it's my pleasure.
我希望你不会觉得我很冒昧
I hope you won't think me rude if I speak.
否则我还是闭口为妙
I wouldn't want to appear forward.
先生  那要看你说什么
Well, sir, that depends on what you say.
如果我夸你是纽约最漂亮的女孩你会认为我很鲁莽吗?
Would you call me reckless if I said you were the prettiest girl in New York?
只是在纽约吗?
Only New York?
我到站了
This is my stop.
我可以陪你走一会儿吗?
May I walk with you a little then?
先生  这样太鲁莽了
That, sir, would be too bold.
早上好
Good morning.
不同的小偷有不同的外号
For every lay we had a different name.
钓鱼者在棍子上装个钩
An "angler" put a hook on the end of a stick
伸到商店门窗后去偷
to drop behind store windows and doors.
潜水者专门在教堂里摸包
An "autumn diver" picked your pocket in church.
獾  找个女孩引人上床
A "badger" gets a fellow into bed with a girl
趁他们行事时掏光他的口袋
then robs his pockets while they're on the go.
珍妮是个女贼  女扒手
Jenny was a "bludget," a girl pickpocket
也是个斑鸠
and a "turtledove."
斑鸠在城里穿成女仆的模样
A turtledove goes uptown dressed like a housemaid
找一大户人家  直接从后门进入
picks out a fine house and goes right through the back door.
偷得神不知鬼不觉
Robs you blind.
做斑鸠需要勇气过人
It takes a lot of sand to be a turtledove.
把圣牌还给我  天啊
I'll have my medal back. Oh, Jesus!
敢再偷我东西
Don't do that again.
给我听好 再偷我的东西
Listen! I said, don't do that
你回五点区  别管我的事
Go back to the Points and leave me to my business
否则我会割开你的喉咙让你去见上帝
or I will open your throat, so help me God.
好吧
All right.
动手吧
Go on then.
我干得出的
I would.
那动手吧
Go on then.
把圣牌还给我
Now give me back my medal.
快点
Make it quick!
我不知道哪个是你的
I don't know which one's yours.
什么事都要我亲手做?
Suppose I help myself to everything?
大概是吧
Suppose you do.
我陪你走一会吧
May I walk with you a little then?
你认为一个人一天能嫌多少钱?
What do you suppose a fellow could earn here in a day?
- 也许我们能合作  - 我想你玩这种游戏有点
- Maybe we could pal in together. - Oh, I think you're a bit
鲁莽  而且我一向独来独往
rough for this sort of game. Besides, I work alone.
独来独往?  你需要向屠夫进贡多少?
Alone? Well, what do you quarter to the Butcher?
- 不需要  - 不需要?
- Me? Nothing. -  Nothing?
屠夫和我有特别协议
The Butcher and me have a special arrangement.
- 我不想再见到你了  - 我不会怪你的
- I don't want to see you again. - Well, I don't blame you.
身揣几个铜板  眼里饱含希望
Pennies in their pockets and hope in their eyes
他们凝视着西方
they peer to the west
眺望着天平线寻找陆地的身影
searching the horizon for a glimpse of land and salvation.
美洲的身影
A glimpse of America.
如此贫困真使人极度不安  斯盖马洪小姐
Seeing all this poverty must be most unsettling, Miss Schermerhorn.
有时富人区的帮派也会来到我们这
Some days, of course, the uptown gangs come down to us.
斯盖马洪家族就是纽约历史最悠久的帮派之一
The Schermerhorns was one of the oldest families in New York.
城市虽然不由他们管理
They didn 't run the city
可他们的影响力却举足轻重
but they was listened to carefully by them that did.
布兰特专员说你希望考察一下五点区的各个层面
Commissioner Brunt said you wished to view
他说'考察一下不需要动员什么人力物力'
the Points in all its splendor and squalor.
除了动用我们以保证安全康斯特布尔
"Spare nothing concerning the conditions," said he.
有康斯特布尔及手下陪同
Yeah, nothing except our safety, constable.
我们会很安全的
I'm sure we can be in no danger while we're in the constable's company.
没问题  女士  作个见证
Quite so, madam. Witness.
- 我们还要继续吗?  - 你居然敢把这东西留在这?
- Shall we continue on? - What, you dare to leave it there?
和银行一样安全  谁都知道这是我的东西
Safe as a bank, Mr. Greeley, since all know it's mine.
- 这人喝醉了吗?  - 此人已死  正如耶稣受难一般
- Is that man drunk? - Dead as Good friday, miss.
- 你好  穆兰尼  - 伙计们
- Good day to you, Mulraney. - Boys.
- 杰克  - 贫民窟还挺友善吧?
- Jack. - Slum sociable?
考察实情  有志改革
Fact- finding. Reforms- studying.
- 我来介绍一下?  - 第5街的斯盖马洪家族
- May I present  ? - The Schermerhorns of fifth Avenue
用不着你来介绍
scarcely require an introduction from you.
斯盖马洪以及他们的女儿
Schermerhorn, indeed. Their daughter. This gentleman, of course
霍雷斯.葛瑞利先生  著名的出版人  很高兴也很荣幸见到你
Horace Greeley, the famous publisher. A pleasure and an honor.
- 《论坛报》的  - 我是威廉·卡丁
- Of the Tribune. -  I'm William Cutting.
你好  卡丁先生
How do you do, Mr. Cutting?
此刻  非常好  多谢  你呢
As of this moment, extremely well, thank you. How do you do?
橙花香  好美妙
Orange blossom. Delicious.
- 卡丁先生是  - 多讨人喜欢的美女啊
- Mr. Cutting is   - What a peach.
她在舞台上一定能大有作为
She could have a fine career on the stage.
五点区的一位    - 幸会  先生
one of Five Points' local   - A pleasure to meet you.
-   首领  - 格瑞里先生
leaders. -  Mr. Greeley.
- 幸会  卡丁先生  - 五点区欢迎你
- Pleased to meet you. - The Points welcomes you.
这些大街小巷对你们都安全无阻
You are welcome to these streets and will pass in safety.
我会保证他们的安全的  多谢  比尔
Oh, I'll see to their safety. Thank you, Bill. There we are.
告辞了  小伙子们  罪犯都是牛皮哄哄的  你看到了
Good day, lads. Criminal's braggadocio, you see.
- 他知道我是谁  - 当然  先生  你在这里可是大名鼎鼎
- He knows who I am. - You're well- known in these parts.
必须得承认这句话是吹捧
I must say that I find that strangely flattering.
- 我从来不喜欢警察  - 不夸张地说
- I never did like crushers. - Well, draw it mild, son.
不是我给他出谋划策  杰克绝对没这么顺风顺水
Happy Jack don't fill his lungs without I tell him he may do so.
你认为我的表挂在灯杆上安全吗  比尔?
Do you think my watch would be safe up on that lamppost, Bill?
你不如挂在那试试?
Why don't you hang it up there and see?
改天吧
Someday.
改天很明智
Someday is right.
你的新马仔?
This a new lad?
不过是又一个投入我温暖怀抱的爱尔兰混小子而已
Just another bastard son of Erin I folded in the warmth of my embrace.
- 嘿！ - 我只想看看你长什么样
- Hey! -  I just want to see your face, son.
无意冒犯
No harm intended.
你得学习很多屠宰的手艺
You get to know a lot butchering meat.
人体由同样的东西组成  血与肉
We're made up of the same things: Flesh and blood
组织  器官
tissue, organs.
我喜欢摆弄猪
I love to work with pigs.
自然界和人肉最近似的东西就是猪肉
The nearest thing in nature to the flesh of a man is the flesh of a pig.
- 猪肉?  - 没错
- Pig, huh? - That's right.
这是给你的  母亲
This is for you, mother.
你来了
There you go.
- 上帝保佑你  卡丁先生  - 上帝保佑你
- God bless you, Mr. Cutting. - God bless you.
- 她肯定不是你亲娘  - 我知道  比尔
- She ain't really my mother. -  I knew that, Bill.
这里是肝脏
This is the liver.
肾脏
The kidneys.
心脏
The heart.
这是薄弱的地方  胃不停地流血
This is a wound. The stomach will bleed and bleed.
这里是致命处  这里是致命处
This is a kill. This is a kill.
大动脉  这里是致命处
The main artery. This is a kill.
你试试
You try.
来吧
Go ahead.
肺  很好  刀刃不要砍在肋骨上
The lung. Good. Don't foul the blade on the rib.
很好  正中动脉
Very good. Main artery.
把目标的血慢慢放出来  让目标死前还能思考一下人生
Bleed him slow. Let him think about it for a while.
慢死  很好
Slow death. Good.
每月拿到5000美元用于城市建设
You'll each bill the city $5000 a month for supplies and services
其中你可提成10%
of which you'll receive 10%.
比尔!  奇罗兰先生正在筹划细节  多谢  先生
Bill! Mr. Killoran will work out the details. Thank you, gentlemen.
在坦慕尼身边就是这么工作的
That's how we do things around Tammany, gentlemen.
那两位是谁?
Who's this then?
多谢了  小伙子们
Thank you, boys.
告辞  先生
Good day, sir.
你脑子里在想什么?
You got something on your mind?
比尔很垂青于你
Bill's taken quite a liking to you.
如果你有所抱负  祝你好运吧
Now, if you're up to something, bene.
只是我不想置身其中
Only I don't want no part in it.
我在地狱门关了16年
I was in Hellgate for 16 years.
我只是想混口饭吃
I'm just trying to make my way is all.
就和你一样
Just like you.
除非你有什么更远大的理想
Unless, of course, you got a better notion?
我没有
No.
处理五点区案件投诉搞的我一天什么事都干不了
I can't get a day's work done for all the good citizens coming in here to harass me about crime in the Points.
有人甚至过分到投诉坦慕尼
Some even go so far as to accuse Tammany
纵容五点区罪案猖獗
of connivance in this so-called rampant criminality.
- 我能怎么办?  - 我没办法  必须得采取一些措施
What am I to do? I can't have this. Something has to be done.
- 你怎么打算?  - 我不知道
- What do you have in mind? - I don't know.
我们也许该吊死几个人
I think maybe we should hang someone.
- 谁?  - 不必是重要人物  一般地
- Who? - No one important, necessarily.
没什么背景的人物就可以
Average men will do. Back-alley amusers with no affiliations.
- 多少?  - 三四个
- How many? - Three or four.
- 到底是几个?  - 四个
- Which? -  Four.
你们被控犯有如下多项罪名
You stand here convicted varyingly
淫荡  抢劫
of lewdness, jack- rolling
偷窃  造假
sneak- thievery, chloral- hydrating
鸡奸  勒索
sodomy, strangulation
腐败贪污
and enthusiastic corruption of the public good.
- 某天我们也会如此  - 抬起头来
- We all go someday, huh? - Chin up.
要上绞架的真不少  这是我的老朋友
Handsome bunch of gallows fruit. There's my old friend.
- 你怎么样  亚瑟?  - 我很好  我很好
- How are you feeling, Arthur? - I'm okay. I'm okay.
向阿姆斯特丹问个好  麦格罗恩差点成他手下败将
Say hello to Amsterdam. Nearly fishhooked McGloin the other day.
- 你好  - 差点
- How do you do? - Nearly.
你穿戴得好整齐
See you dressed for the occasion.
你了解我的  我最注重仪表的
You know me, always like to look me best.
不错
That's the spirit.
这小金盒真不错  一块钱卖给我
Nice locket. I'll give you a dollar for it.
是我母亲的
It's me mother's.
一块半如何?
Dollar and a half?
成交
Done.
我们会想念你的  亚瑟
We'll miss you, Arthur.
- 天国再见  谢墨斯  - 热玉米!
- See you in the hot country, Seamus. -  Hot corn!
刚出炉的热玉米  热玉米!
Ears of early white corn! Hot corn!
我的儿子来了吗?
Is my son present here?
我的小宝贝在哪?
Where's my little fella?
看着你爸
Look at your dad.
永别了  亲爱的孩子
Farewell, dear boy.
我从没做过坏事  也没害过人
I never struck a foul blow, nor turned a card.
上帝会像迎接老友一样欢迎我
May God greet me as a friend.And grace my fears relieved
那晚改良派举行了舞会
How precious Did that grace appear That night, the reformers held a dance.
这就是五点区
That was the Five Points, all right.
白天绞人  晚上跳舞
Hangings of a morning, dancings of an evening.
她肯定对我有意思
-  Sure meself, but
从她冲我笑的样子看得出来
it's not a matter of words. I can tell by the way she smiles at me.
- 她对很多人都笑  - 先生
- She smiles at a lot of people. -  Sir.
你不了解他
You don't know her.
给一位爱尔兰战士赏点小钱  年轻人
A penny of gratitude for a fighting Irishman, young sir.
- 你是克立人?  - 是的  先生
- You from Kerry? - I am, sir. I am.
- 不是很多  别介意  - 感谢你
- It ain't much. - Thank you, sir. Thank you.
女士们  先生们  我们很高兴
Ladies and gentlemen, we are delighted to see
在教会组织的年度舞会上看到这么多年轻的面孔
so many young faces at our first annual Mission dance.
会是一场开放热闹的舞会
This'll be a real ballum rancum, eh?
教会欢迎来自各界的基督教徒
The Mission welcomes Christians of every stamp
能招待今晚来参加舞会的罗马天主教朋友我们尤其高兴
and we are particularly happy to greet our Roman Catholic friends  who join us here tonight.
- 女士们  跟我来 - 可以跳个舞吗？
- Ladies! Come with me. Come with me. - Shall we dance?
舞会很快就要开始了
We're going to start the dancing in just a moment.
不
No.
- 晚上好  牧师  - 晚上好  陛下
- Good evening, Reverend. - Good evening, Your Holiness.
晚上好  牧师
Good evening, Reverend.
你应该把胡子刮得干净点
Looks as though you should have shaved closer.
晚上好  牧师  请求您的谅解
Good evening, Reverend. I do beg your pardon.
怎么称呼?
Miss  ?
- 爱华亭  - 爱华亭小姐
- Everdeane. - Miss Everdeane.
你们不介意的话  请到这边来  多谢
Now, gentlemen, over here, if you don't mind. Thank you.
打开  拿着
Open it. Hold it up.
对着镜子
Into the mirror.
就他了
That one.
我们的皇后选中你了
Our queen has chosen.
先生
Sir
- 你的女伴  - 好了
- your lady. -  Right.
通常教堂礼拜的时间是6点到8点
Regular services are held at the church at 6 and 8.
去死吧
Go to hell.
- 你这是在干什么?  - 我在跳舞
- What do you think you're doing? - Dancing.
- 我问你为什么选我?  - 不关你的事
- I said, why'd you pick me? - That's none of your business.
可否说来听听?
Would you mind telling me?
对不起
I'm sorry.
该死
Goddamn it!
对不起  跳舞我不拿手
I'm sorry. I'm not much of a dancer.
别心浮气燥
Just try to keep calm.
- 我从来踩不准步点  - 最好别看下面
- I never been to a stepping- ken before. -  It's best not to look down.
愿意的话你可以揽紧点
You can hold me tighter if you like.
- 好的  - 好的
- All right? - Aye.
你为什么不和约翰尼跳舞?
So why didn't you dance with Johnny?
因为
Because
我不想要他
I didn't want him.
我不想这样
I'm not wanting this.
- 等等  - 怎么了?
- Wait. - What?
等等
Wait.
这个怎么解开?
How does this open?
绑上很费工夫的  我们要在此呆一整晚
It takes too long to lace back up. We'll be here all night.
行了  我来解开它
Sure, all right, I'll take it off.
我有过孩子  剖腹取出来了
There was a baby. They cut it out.
对不起
I'm sorry.
没关系
Oh, it's fine.
你身上有伤疤吗?
Have you got any scars?
有几个吧
One or two.
这是什么?
What's that, then?
那个?
That?
卡丁先生送我的礼物
It's a gift from Mr. Cutting.
礼物?
A gift?
礼物
A gift.
是你的生日礼物?
Was it your birthday?
不是
No.
那你回赠他什么?
What you give him, then?
这个与你无关
The answer to that has nothing to do with you.
- 别告诉我你生气了  - 没有
- Don't tell me you're angry with me. - No.
我和你已经结束了
I'm through with you.
你比大多数男人说得都快
Well, you're quicker than most fellows.
通常他们会等到事后才说
Generally, they wait till afterwards.
我对屠夫穿过的破鞋没兴趣
I ain't interested in the Butcher's leavings.
比尔说胆小鬼就别来了
Hey! Bill says keep clear of the pikers.
- 15比1  大块头马龙  - 阿姆斯特丹
- Fifteen to one, Bug-Eye Moran. - Amsterdam!
每个人都为屠夫打工
Everyone was working for the Butcher.
我们替他跑腿  帮他挣钱
We ran his errands, made his money
拿点小钱还得说'多谢  先生'
took a piece and said, "Thank you, sir."
- 先生们  这里要抄查  - 包括特威德在内
- Gentlemen, it's a raid! - Even Tweed.
- 格斗结束了  - 包括我在内
- The fight's over. - Even me.
- 好了 你这蠢货  - 我父亲的儿子
- All right, you stupid   - My father's son.
- 怎么回事?  - 对不起  比尔
- What the hell is this? - Sorry, Bill.
城市里是禁止举行拳击的  我准许
The city ordinance against boxiana's a blight, I grant you, but some
你说个不停 而我的钱都快跑光了  快出去把赌金收回来
I'm losing revenue while you speechify. Collect those bets!
先生  还没个结果我怎么去收?
How do I collect if no one won the fight?
此活动非法  你就凭这个作借口  明白吗?
This counts as a "no decision." You got that covered, right?
难道我没打点警察局吗?
Didn't anybody pay off the police?
我们打点的是市属警察  这是都会警察
We paid the Municipal Police. This is Metropolitan Police.
- 我的损失你都得补偿  - 特威德先生
- You'll repay me every cent. - Mr. Tweed
- 没轮到你多嘴  - 让他说
- Who asked for your opinion? -  Let him speak!
他不听命于你
He don't answer to you.
法律规定城市里不允许拳击  对吧?
The law says there's no boxing in the city, right?
- 是的  在城市里  - 那么  城市的边界在哪里?
- That's right. In the city. - Well, where does the city end?
第75轮比赛的胜者
The winner, in the 75th round
让我们感谢一个人  他以他的远见和谋略
Allow me to acknowledge the man whose vision and enterprise made possible
使高贵的拳击比赛能够
the staging of this noble combat
在一个激动人心而又完全合法的环境下进行
in these awe-inspiring and entirely legal surroundings:
威廉·卡丁先生
Mr. William Cutting!
以及他的年轻助理
And   And his young associate!
好的  你干得很好
That's you, boy.
过来  到这来  过来  孩子
Come on, get in there. Come on, son.
你干得真棒  你觉得爽吗？
You done very good. How do you like them apples?
我们干得漂亮  我们干得不错
We done good. We done all right.
- 在此提请大家注意    - 刚才的比赛很精彩
- While I have your attention   - It was a good show.
更多的奇观在我的博物馆等着你们
may I remind you of the wonders that await you
博物馆座落于百老汇
at my muzeum located on Broadway!
P.T.巴南姆奇观展览
P.T. Barnum's Gallery of Wonders!
- 那是我的钱  - 别碰我的钱包
- That's my money! - Get your hands out of me pockets!
屁护在强者的羽翼之下的感觉好奇怪
It's a funny feeling being took under the wing of a dragon.
比你想象的还温暖
It's warmer than you think.
这里可以见证我们国家的建立  卡丁先生
That's the building of our country right there, Mr. Cutting.
美国在成长
Americans aborning.
我没看到什么美国人  我只见到入侵者
I don't see no Americans. I see trespassers.
黑人一角钱肯做的工作  爱尔兰人五分钱就肯了
Irish harps will do a job for a nickel what a nigger does for a dime
而原来白人可以拿到两角五的
and a white man used to get a quarter for.
他们作了什么?说一件他们的贡献
What have they done? Name one thing they've contributed.
- 投票  - 你会说投票吧?
- Votes. - Votes, you say?
他们的大主教说选谁他们就选谁  那么是谁告诉大主教的呢?
They vote how the archbishop tells them. And who tells him?
戴着尖帽远在天边的罗马教皇
Their king in the pointy hat what sits on his throne in Rome.
比尔对爱尔兰人有种复杂的感情
Bill's got mixed feelings as regards the Irish.
如果在参与选举时把票都投给坦慕尼的话
Deliver these good and fervent folk to the polls on a regular basis
能够带来数量相当可观的选票
and there'll be a handsome price for each vote goes Tammany's way.
我父亲为这个国家的今天而献出生命
My father gave his life making this country what it is.
他于公元1814年7月25日被英国人杀害
Murdered by the British with all his men on the 25th of July, anno Domini 1814.
你认为我会帮你违背他的遗愿
You think I'm gonna help you befoul his legacy
把国家交给从未为此奋斗过的人手上吗?
by giving this country over to them what's had no hand in fighting for it?
为什么?只因为他们远道而来  满身虱虫  向你乞讨吗?
Why? Because they come off a boat, crawling with lice and begging for soup?
你是一位伟大的斗士  我知道  可你永远不能再动用武力了
You're a great one for the fighting, I know, but you can't fight forever.
- 我可以到南边去战斗  - 你会的
- I can go down doing it. - And you will.
你说什么?
What did you say?
我说你在逃避未来
I said, you're turning your back on the future.
不是我们的未来
Not our future.
那份文件使你成为美国公民  这份使你成为联盟军的士兵
That document makes you a citizen. This makes you a private in the Union Army.
为你的国家战斗去吧
Now go fight for your country.
下一位
Next.
♪ 我们一百多人航行到达美国♪
Well, meself and a hundred more to America sailed o'er
在这签字  或者按手印
Sign here, son. Or make your mark.
你现在是军人了  一日管三餐
You're in the Army now. Three square meals a day.
♪ 我们期待能在这里找到财富♪
Our fortunes to be made we were thinkin'
先领制服  再领武器
Uniforms first, then weapons.
- 我已经两天没吃东西了  - 继续走
- I haven't eaten in two days. - Keep moving, men.
♪ 到了美国佬的地盘  他们把枪塞到我们手上♪
When we got to Yankee land they shoved a gun into our hands
♪ 并说道“帕蒂  你必须为林肯而战”♪
Saying, "Paddy, you must go and fight for Lincoln"
这是你的枪  小心在船上别弄湿了
There's your musket. Keep it dry on the boat.
- 子弹也一样  - 我们要去哪?
- Same for this cartridge case. - Where are we going?
- 听说是田纳西  - 那是哪里?
- I heard Tennessee. -  Where's that?
♪ 这里除了战争一无所有  杀人的大炮在咆哮♪
There is nothing here but war where the murdering cannons roar
♪ 我多希望自己还在都柏林的老家里♪
And I wish I was at home in dear old Dublin
你看他们会不会马上给饭吃?
Do they feed us now, do you think?
孩子们  孩子们
My children! My children!
我们之间的分歧必须调和
We must heal the divisions between us.
战争必须结束
This war must cease.
南北方应该统一
North and South must stand united!
五点区教会上演<汤姆叔叔的小屋>
你是个骗子  垃圾
You're a liar! Rubbish!
- 戏完了会怎么样?  - 戏完了大家就一起起哄
- What happens at the finish, then? - Then we have ourselves a rowdy- dow.
- 你从来没看过戏吗?  - 没有
- Ain't you been to the theater before? - No.
莱格雷先生  放下你的鞭子
Mr. Legree, lay down your whip.
艾丽莎小姐  和谢尔比先生握手吧
Miss Eliza, join hands with Mr.Shelby.
托普西  亲爱的小托普西  亲抚汤姆叔叔的额头
And, Topsy, dear little Topsy, cradle Uncle Tom's head.
让黑鬼去死吧
Leave the nigger dead!
放我下来
Get me down!
打倒联盟
Down with the Union!
- 打倒联盟  - 打倒联盟
- Down with the Union! - Down with the Union!
- 为了爱尔兰人的血债  - 比尔  卧倒
- For the blood of the Irish! - Bill, get down!
有人向屠夫开枪
Somebody's popped the Butcher!
掐死这个鼠辈
Stifle that rat bastard down!
主啊  宽恕我吧
God, forgive me.
谁派你来的?
Whose man are you?
说清楚点  大声点
Speak smart and speak up.
他说什么?
What's he saying, boy?
他可能在向上帝告解
I think he's making his peace with God.
见他妈的鬼!他该向我告解
The hell with that. He makes peace with me.
今晚我要听你忏悔  该死的狗娘养的爱尔兰鬼
I'm hearing confession tonight, you mother-whoring Irish nigger!
谁派你来的?  这个国家是说英文的
Whose man are you? We speak English in this country.
谁派你来的?  看见刀子了吗?
Whose man are you? See this knife?
我要用这把刀教你说英语
I'm gonna teach you to speak English with this fucking knife!
谁派你来的?
Whose man are you?
看来问不出什么了
Well, that didn't tell us very much.
这马甲不错
Fine waistcoat.
真遗憾  没有办法补了
Shame about it. I don't think it can be mended.
要不要留作纪念品?
Will I keep it as a souvenir?
莱格雷呢?莫普西呢?
Where's Legree? Where's Mopsy?
演员们  开演了
Tragedians, let's continue. Intermission is over!
真是一出活生生的莎翁戏
Now that was bloody Shakespearean.
- 什么?  - 你知道莎士比亚是谁吧  小伙子?
- What? - Do you know who Shakespeare was?
《钦定圣经译本》的作者
He was the fellow who wrote the King James Bible.
先生  我不知道你在讲什么鬼话
I don't know what you're talking about.
因为你是个蠢笨无知粗鲁的爱尔兰狗崽子
That's because you're a thick, ignorant, barbarous Irish whelp.
就像你父亲一样
Just like your father.
够了  够了
That's it.
你妨碍我行事  破坏我计划  就跟其他愚蠢的爱尔兰人一样
Tear my head off and destruct the world, just like the rest of the stupid Irish.
- 所以我从未与你父亲并肩战斗过  - 放开我  你这个疯子
- That's why I never ran with your dad. - Get off me, you crazy bastard!
意思是'如果你不够强壮  你就得放聪明点'
It means, if you're not strong, you'd better be smart.
我搞不清你是太蠢还是太聪明
I don't know if you're being too clever or too dumb.
无论如何  请牢记这话
Whichever it is, just remember this much.
不管你父亲有多少缺点  他始终是个热爱同胞手足的人
For all his faults, your father was a man who loved his people.
阿姆斯特丹!  阿姆斯特丹!
Amsterdam! Amsterdam!
纽约在叫你
New York is calling you.
看  不知道该叫什么名堂
Look at that. What in Christ's name is that?
黑非洲的节奏配上爱尔兰式的鼓点
Rhythms of the Dark Continent thrown into the kettle with an Irish shindig.
多搅和几次  再拿出来  成了美国式的大杂烩
Stir it around a few times, pull it out, it's a fine American mess.
黑鬼跳捷格舞
A jig doing a jig.
小纪念品
A little keepsake.
- 你真好  先生  - 和我上楼去吧  比尔
- Good on you, sir. - Come upstairs with me, Bill.
我以前和你好过吗?
Have I ever had you before?
那你不能叫我的教名
So you don't call me by my Christian name.
比尔  感谢上帝你平安无事
Bill! Thank God you're all right.
我一听到消息就尽快赶来了
I heard the news and came as quick as I could.
你就像死神一样及时
You're as timely as the Angel of Death.
比尔  你不是讽刺我来这吧?  你在暗示什么?
Bill, you're not suggesting that I would stoop to what you're suggesting?
别浪费口水了  如果我认为是你干的  你早上天堂去了
Stop slabbering. If I thought it was you, you'd be in a wooden coat.
我肩膀上有个洞  很疼  要么请喝杯酒闭上嘴
The hole in my shoulder hurts, so have a drink and shut up.
要么闭上嘴出去
Or shut up and get out.
我还是来杯酒吧
I believe I'll have a drink.
小心  特威德  那女人可有花柳病
Careful, Tweedy, the mort's frenchified.
不  我很干净的  走  去酒吧
No, no, I'm clean. Come on, let's go to the bar.
- 珍妮  - 比尔
- Jenny. - Bill.
我会绑紧一点
It's gotta be tight.
她喜欢让我流泪
She loves to make me cry.
你能行的
You can take it.
这是我的手下
There's my boy.
没事的
It's all right.
为屠夫干杯
To the Butcher.
我们对他感恩戴德
We're all much obliged.
永远
Forever.
- 为屠夫干杯  - 为屠夫干杯
- Bill the Butcher. - To the Butcher.
你别呆在这里  约翰尼
Why don't you get out of here, Johnny?
快走
Go on. Go.
五点区有没操过你的人吗?
Is there anyone in the Five Points you haven't fucked?
有！就是你
YES! You!
冷静
Calm down!
你敢亲我就咬你
Try it and I'll bite you!
如果你敢咬我    你只不过吓吓我  是吗?
If you were gonna bite me, I don't think you'd warn me, huh?
试试看
Find out.
我睡不着
I can't sleep.
希望你别介意我们俩今晚睡在这里
I hope you don't mind us laying out tonight here, sir.
你喜欢她哪一点?
Whatever takes your fancy, my young friend.
是不是肩膀疼的你睡不着?
Is it your shoulder that's keeping you up?
不是  我一向睡得不多
No, I don't never sleep too much.
我睡觉时要睁一只眼  可我只有一只眼
I have to sleep with one eye open. I only got one eye, right?
你多大了  阿姆斯特丹?
How old are you, Amsterdam?
我也确定不了
I'm not too sure.
从来没有算过
I never did figure it.
我47了
I'm 47.
四十七岁了
Forty-seven years old.
你知道我怎么这么长命吗?  活了这么多年?
You know how I stayed alive this long? All these years?
恐惧
Fear.
某些让人恐惧的行为产生的效果
The spectacle of fearsome acts.
偷我东西的人  我斩了他的手
Somebody steals from me, I cut off his hands.
冒犯我的人  我割下他的舌头
He offends me, I cut out his tongue.
胆敢反抗我  我割下他的头  挑在矛尖上
He rises against me, I cut off his head, stick it on a pike
挂得高高的  让行人都看得到
and raise it high up so all in the streets can see.
如此来维持正常的秩序
That's what preserves the order of things.
恐惧
Fear.
今晚这个人
That one tonight
是何许人?
who was he?
什么也不是
A nobody.
只是个胆小鬼
A coward.
结局是如此地不光彩
What an ignominious end that would have been.
15年前我杀了最后一个值得我尊敬的人  从那以后
I killed the last honorable man 15 years ago. Since then, it's
你在楼下见过他的肖像吗?
You've seen his portrait downstairs?
你的嘴是不是被口水沾住了?  我正问你话呢
Is your mouth glued up with cunny juice? I asked you a question!
我说我看见了  先生
I said, I seen it, sir.
你有种爆怒凶狠的气质  我喜欢
Oh, you got a murderous rage in you, and I like it.
血气方刚  很好
It's life boiling up inside of you. It's good.
牧师和我的生活准则是一致的
The Priest and me, we lived by the same principles.
不同的信仰使我们分道扬镳
It was only faith divided us.
这就是他的赏赐
He give me this, you know.
我被打得最惨的一次
That was the finest beating I ever took.
鼻青脸肿
My face was pulp
肚子也破了  肋骨全折了
my guts was pierced and my ribs was all mashed up.
他过来结果我的时候
And when he came to finish me
我都无法盯着他的眼睛
I couldn't look him in the eye.
他饶了我一命因为他想让我耻辱地活着
He spared me because he wanted me to live in shame.
他是个了不起的人物
This was a great man.
了不起的人物
A great man.
所以我干脆剜了这只眼
So I cut out the eye that looked away.
用蓝纸包着送给他
Sent it to him, wrapped in blue paper.
如果我瞎了也可与他战斗我会两只眼都剜出来
I would have cut them both out if I could have fought him blind.
我终于重振雄风
Then I rose back up again with a full heart
用他自己的血埋葬了他
and buried him in his own blood.
好精彩
Well done.
我所杀的人里唯一让我忘不了的
He was the only man I ever killed worth remembering.
我没有儿子
I never had a son.
文明正在衰退
Civilization is crumbling.
上帝保佑你
God bless you.
如果你有话要说
If you got anything to say
现在可以说了
now is the time to say it.
他到底是你什么人?  珍妮
Who is he to you, Jenny?
我12岁那年
I was 12 years old.
母亲去世了  我无家可归
My mother was dead. I was living in a doorway.
他带我回家  照顾我
He took me in, took care of me
用他的方式
in his own way.
我打了胎之后
After they cut out the baby
他不喜欢留下疤痕的女孩
Well, he doesn't fancy girls that scarred up.
你应该想得到
You should know in your own mind
除非我求他  他根本不会碰我的
that he never laid a hand on me until I asked him to.
你是谁?
Who are you?
先生们  先生们  向你们致以最热烈的欢迎
Gentlemen. Fine gentlemen, you are most welcome
此地妙景纷呈  美不胜收
to this palace of wonder and enchantment
媲美中桑鲁卓描绘的最美妙的幻境
where visions to rival the finest imaginings of Scheherezade  and her tales from the perfumed nights of Arabia
令人目不暇接
will greet your famished eyes.
我怎么为这位亚麻头发的日耳曼美人开价呢?
What am I bid for this flaxen-haired Teutonic beauty?
请尽情欣赏这些美艳动人的异国尤物
Feast your eyes on the magnificent plumage of these exotic creatures.
先生们  想必已经看清楚笼中的依人小鸟
Gentlemen, you've seen our caged birds.
你如何才能令她们歌唱呢?
Well, how'd you like to make them sing?
我来看看你们出的钱  她们终会为你歌唱的
Let me see the color of your money, and they could be singing for you.
主将圣灵的力量注入我的脊梁
May God put the steel of the Holy Spirit in my spine
将圣母的爱放入我心
and the love of the Blessed Virgin in my heart.
阿门
Amen.
别紧张
Easy now.
你刚才说什么?
What did you say?
他没说实话
He's not who he says he is.
他没说实话?
He's not who he says he is?
怎么开价?  怎么开价?  怎么开价
What am I bid? What am I bid? What am I bid?
亏他还把你当朋友
Count your blessings he considers you a friend.
他日日夜夜处心积虑  就是考虑一件事 杀你的万全之策
The only thing he considers, every day and every night, is how best to kill you.
你长着一条嚼不烂的舌头  你是不是想我把它割下来
You got a loose tongue in your head. You want me to take it out for you?
然后塞到你的屁眼里去才好?
I'll bury it right up your fundament where it belongs.
我看穿你了  你很心虚
I can read right through you. You're empty
他叫瓦伦
His name is Vallon!
别动手  比尔  他名字叫瓦伦
Don't do it, Bill. His name's Vallon.
这些来自中国的人好古怪
They're curious people, these Celestials.
别信他
Don't trust this guy.
- 你知道他为什么穿短袖吗?  - 为什么?
- Know why he wears short sleeves? -  Why?
是为了让人看到他什么也没藏
So everyone can see he's got nothing stashed.
天啊  希望短袖不会成为时尚
Jesus, let's hope that never becomes the fashion.
约翰尼
Johnny.
起来
Get up.
女士们  先生们  在此提请您注意
Ladies and gentlemen, if I may have your kind attention.
某些人已经注意到了
As some of you have surely noticed
我们的朋友及捐助人威廉.卡丁先生
our friend and benefactor Mr. William Cutting
今晚穿了件与众不同的马甲
is tonight wearing a waistcoat of certain distinction.
我们.
Might we
我们呼吁他出来为大家表演
Might we tonight appeal to him to favor us
集技巧  勇气  胆量于一身的激动人心的节目
with another exciting exhibition of skill  courage, daring and drama!
- 大马士革之剑 - 印第安战斧
- The Sword of Damascus! - The Tomahawk!
比尔要表演了
Bill's going up.
显显你的刀法
Show us your knives.
露一手 孩子
Strut your stuff, Billy boy.
大马士革之剑
Sword of Damascus!
- 蜘蛛之吻  - 血流成河
- The Spider's Kiss! - The River of Blood!
- 早安荣耀  - 死亡之风
- The Morning Glory! - The Wheel of Death!
- 威廉.退尔  - 蝴蝶
- William Tell! - The Butterfly!
- 印第安战斧  - 蜘蛛女之吻
- The Tomahawk! - The Spider's Kiss!
屠夫的徒弟
The Butcher's Apprentice!
The Butcher's Apprentice.
- 请继续表演  - 请继续表演
- Command performance. - Command performance.
- 请继续表演  - 你去哪了?
- Command performance. - Where have you been?
我将遵令献艺
A command performance indeed!
- 我要你离开这里  - 别这样
- I want you to Get out of here. - Don't do it.
为此  我必须征得我表演节目的老搭档
And for this I must beg the indulgence of my former assistant
的允诺
in matters of impalement.
屠夫的嫡传弟子的允诺
The Butcher's original apprentice.
你看如何  珍?  为了纪念过往的合作再来一次?
What do you say, Jen? One more time for the sweet souvenir?
来吧
Come on.
别动
Don't you do it.
好女孩  珍妮
Good girl, Jenny.
- 别害怕  - 好一位女士!
- Don't be afraid. - What a woman.
晚上好  比尔
Good evening, Bill.
她不会有事的
She'll be all right.
- 还记得吗?  - 当然
- Remember this? -  Of course.
不穿披肩你会更惬意  爱华亭小姐
You may feel more comfortable without that garment, Miss Everdeane.
你得给我偷件新的来  比尔
You'll have to filch me a new one, Bill.
你口袋里有东西吗?
Anything in your pockets tonight?
我还没开始工作呢
Oh, I ain't started working yet.
我送你的那个小金盒呢?
What about that locket that I gave you?
我道歉  亲爱的  捡起来吧
Apologies, my dear. Pick it up.
可怜的小美人
Whoopsie-daisy!
这东西被我给毁了
Now it's good and broke.
今晚状态真不好
I can't seem to get anything right tonight.
你够胆再来个压轴表演吗?
You got the sand to give them a grand finale?
你的准头好一点还差不多
Maybe when you're aiming a little straighter.
还是让你见血了  珍  这破音乐听够了
Still got some blood in you, Jen? Enough of this heathen music!
把那帮该死的猴子赶走  开始演奏  伙计们
Get rid of these goddamn monkeys. Strike up, boys!
准备好了?  这是美国之夜
Ready? This is a night for Americans!
- 珍妮  - 把你的手拿开
- Jenny! - Get your hands off me.
- 快走  - 把你的手拿开
- Go away. - Get your hands off me!
走
Move.
阿姆斯特丹!
Amsterdam!
脱帽
Hats off!
我们在心中永远怀念那些死去的弟兄们
We hold in our hearts the memory of our fallen brothers
他们的鲜血留在我们每天走过的街道上
whose blood stains the very streets we walk today.
同时我们在今晚  也追悼我们的敌人的首领
Also on this night, we pay tribute to the leader of our enemies
一位可敬之人  慷慨赴死
an honorable man who crossed over bravely
为他的信仰而战
fighting for what he believed in.
为了打败敌人我只能结束了他的生命
To defeat my enemy, I extinguish his life
正如我毁灭这杯中的火焰一般
and consume him as I consume these flames.
向牧师瓦伦致敬
In honor of Priest Vallon.
哀悼牧师瓦伦
All grieve Priest Vallon!
那里是弱点
That's a wound.
天啊
God!
我向大家介绍牧师瓦伦的儿子
I want you all to meet the son of Priest Vallon.
我对他关怀备至
I took him under my wing
看看现在他怎么报答我的
and see how I'm repaid?
- 这个畜生  - 先救我一命
- You bastard! - Saves my life one day
为的是他日像小贼一样图谋我的性命
so he can kill me the next like a sneak-thief
而不是像男子汉一样地公平决斗
instead of fighting like a man.
这种行为卑鄙地玷污了你高尚的父亲
A base defiler, unworthy of a noble name.
天啊
God! Jesus!
好了  麦格罗恩  把他抬上桌
All right, that'l do, McGloin. Splay him out.
黑人不许看  你  你想偷窥
This show ain't for blackies. You! You get to watch.
听见吗?  黑鬼!
Don't you hear, nigger?
这可是鲜肉  知道我什么意思吗?
This is fresh meat. You know what I mean?
我们得先把肉软化一下
We need to tenderize this meat a little bit.
好吧  现在吻别这张年轻英俊的脸吧
All right, let's kiss good night to that pretty young face of yours.
不
No!
大家想要什么?  肋排还是里脊  腰还是小腿?
What'l it be, then? Rib or chop? Loin or shank?
- 肝  - 脾
- The liver! - The spleen!
- 舌头  - 肾
- The tongue! - Kidneys!
- 肺  - 肝 - 腿
-  The lungs! -  The liver! - His legs!
- 舌头  - 肾
- The tongue! - The kidneys!
- 胃  - 心  心
- The stomach! - The heart! The heart!
心?  这小子没有心
The heart? This boy has no heart.
- 宰了他  - 宰了他
- Then kill him! - Kill him!
他不配死  他不配死在我手里
He ain't earned a death. He ain't earned a death at my hands.
不配  他将被打上耻辱的烙印出入人群
No. He'll walk amongst you marked with shame
成为巴南姆博物馆的怪物
a freak worthy of Barnum's Muzeum of Wonders.
屠夫手下唯一放生的人
Go only man spared by the Butcher.
不  比尔
No, Bill!
不  不
No! No!
不 不  不
No! No! No!
不  不  不
这边  这边
Here. Here!
走这边  快点  快点
This way. Come on. Come on!
我想给你看点东西
I wanna show you something.
我母亲的遗骨也埋在这里
My mother's bones share this grave.
从13岁起我每赚一美元就存下10美分
I've saved 10 cents out of every dollar I've ever earned since I was 13.
一共是215美元
That's $ 215.
靠偷以及其他方式赚来的
That's $215 for bludgeting and the rest.
我就想给你看这东西
This is what I wanted to show you.
你身体好了我们就去这地方
This is where we're gonna go as soon as you get well.
旧金山  加利福尼亚
San francisco, California.
那里想要什么就有什么
You can have anything you want out there.
这些人只是用手就从河里淘金子
These men are pulling gold right out of the river with their own hands.
我们在这里  需要到那去
We're here, and we need to get there.
从这起程  沿海岸往南走
We start here, go down around here
再往北到旧金山
to San francisco.
最快的路
Shortest way to go.
你愿和我一起去吧?
Would you go with me?
没必要开枪  小姐  也没必要指着我
No need to fire that, miss. Or even aim it.
我只是来探望你受伤的朋友而已
An audience with your mangled friend is all I want.
我的棒上有44条刀痕
I got 44 notches in my club.
知道是为什么吗?
Do you know what they're for?
用于死的时候提醒我所欠上帝的债
To remind me of what I owe God when I die.
我父亲也死在战斗中
My father was killed in battle too.
在爱尔兰  在街头
In Ireland, in the streets
与那些在种族屠杀中巧取豪夺的人战斗
fighting those who would take as their privilege what could only be got and held by the decimation of a race.
这种战争已经有上千年历史了
That war is 1000 years old or more.
我们希望不会把野蛮带到美国
We never expected it to follow us here.
可惜希望落空
It didn't.
我们一落脚就发现它早已在这恭候多时了
It was waiting for us when we landed.
你父亲想为他的同胞在这个国家找一块安生之地
Your father tried to carve out a corner in this country for his tribe.
这就是他以及他的死兔帮的使命
That was him. That was his Dead Rabbits.
我时常想如果他能长寿一些
I often wondered, if he'd lived a bit longer
他会不会想要做更多好事?
would he have wanted a bit more?
那他去世时你为何还要搜他的口袋?
Why'd you rifle through his pockets then?
为了保管他的遗物
For safekeeping.
也许你用得着它
I thought maybe you could do with it.
血该留在刀刃上
The blood stays on the blade.
这只可怜的兔子真是我见犹怜
That's a sorry-looking pelt.
这三个月里来它一直健康乖巧的
And it's been so nice and quiet for the last three months.
如此罪行你能泰然处之吗?
Tell me, this charge, does it sit uneasy with you?
不行  其实我挺
No, it's
不安的  比尔
not uneasy, Bill.
不行  我没法泰然处之
No, I wouldn't say that.
可是我效忠于法律
But my allegiance is to the law.
我们的职责就是维护法律
I'm paid to uphold the law.
你到底在说什么呀?
What in heaven's name are you talking about?
你可能有顾虑  别以为这样会被指责
You may have misgivings, but don't go believing that.That way lies damnation.
我没有被指责的危险  比尔
I'm in no danger of damnation, Bill.
你给我听着
Here's the thing.
我对你那些道义上的困惑没丁点兴趣
I don't give a tuppenny fuck about your moral conundrum
你这个猪脑袋
you meatheaded shit-sack.
面前就是这样一件事
That's more or less the thing.
我要你亲自去办  就是你
And I want you to go out there   You, nobody else.
你手下的奴才别插手
None of your little minions. I want you to go out there
我要你亲自去
and I want you
我要你去惩治
to punish the person
那个家伙
who's responsible
那个杀害了这只可怜的兔子的家伙
for murdering this poor little rabbit.
你明白了吗?
Is that understood?
是的
Right.
走之前先尝几口鲜肉吧
Help yourself to some decent meat on the way out.
该死
Damn it.
是你吗?
Is that you, boy?
我开枪其实没其他意思
I didn't mean nothing by that shot, you know.
只是你吓了我一跳
You scared me is all.
你该知道我绝对不会伤害你的
Sure you know I'd never do you harm.
出来吧  小伙子
Come out now, lad.
还记得你父亲和我吗?
Remember your father and me.
当时你是不是太小了?把杰克叔叔给忘了?
Are you too young to remember your old Uncle Jack?
时间过得真快
Oh, the times we had.
你知道我不会伤害你的
You know I won't hurt you.
他死了吗?
Is he dead?
我去叫安德鲁  安德鲁  过来看
I'm gonna get Andrew. Andrew, come see.
安德鲁  过来看  快  都快点
Andrew, come see, quick! Everybody, quick!
搞得人人自危  下一位该到哪位政客了?
This is bad for everybody. What's next? Dead politicians?
对我来说  你们6条命没他一条命值钱
I could spare half a dozen of you easier than I can spare him.
这小子挺有干劲
Still, I think it shows dash.
给这小子多一点时间  我们会和他算总帐的
Give the boy some time. We'll settle with a good dustup.
每天有好多同胞从船上下来
There's more of us coming off these ships every day.
听说每周有15000爱尔兰人到来
I heard 15,000 Irish a week.
可我们为什么还是怕本地帮?
And we're afraid of the Natives.
如果我们团结起来那就不止是个帮派  简直是只军队
Get all of us together, we ain't got a gang. We got an army.
我们需要一颗火种  对吧?  一颗火种
And all you neet a spark, right? Just one spark.
星星之火  可以燎原
Something to wake us all up.
出卖你的人是我
It was me played you false.
- 我后悔刚才说了那话  - 后悔?
- I'd take it back if I could. - Take it back?
约翰尼  我要杀了你
Johnny, I gotta kill you.
滚出五点区  别再回来
Get out of the Points and don't come back.
你去哪  小伙子?
Where you going, boyo?
跟我来
Come along.
Come on.
告诉我们  你惹了什么麻烦?
Tell us, John, what's the trouble?
没麻烦  比尔
No trouble, Bill.
还在为你的那些朋友保密?
Still hiding out with your friends?
不是  我和他们不是一路的  比尔
No, I'm   I'm not with them, Bill.
我和你是一路的  和本地帮是一路的
I'm with you. I'm with the Natives.
据我所知  你一直都是本地帮的
You always was a Native as far as I'm interested, John
直到你成为叛徒之前
till you became a stag.
你说你是本地帮的  你知道本地帮的人是什么样的吗?
You tell me you're a Native. Do you want to know what a Native is?
本地帮的好汉
A Native is a man
为了国家不惜流血牺牲
what's willing to give his life for his country
就像我父亲那样
like my father done.
你愿意这么做吗?小朋友?
Are you willing to do that, my young friend?
约翰  约翰尼!
John. Johnny!
约翰尼?
Johnny?
约翰
John
我伤得很重
It hurts too much.
杀了我吧
Just kill me.
求你了  求你了
Please, please.
求你了
Please.
对不起  约翰尼
I'm sorry, Johnny.
天主圣母玛利亚
Holy Mary, mother of God, pray for us sinners
请为我们罪人祈祷  无论是现在还是临终时  阿门
now and at the hour of our death. Amen.
安息吧  妈妈
Rest in peace, Ma.
你在这里做什么?
What are you doing here, boyo?
这黑鬼上教堂干什么?
What's a nigger doing in this church?
死兔帮应该怎么对付本地帮?
What's a Dead Rabbit doing with the Natives?
本地帮没有黑鬼  本地帮和死兔帮信仰相同
There's no niggers in the Natives. Natives and Rabbits is one thing.
可是黑鬼跑到教堂里来却是另一码事
A nigger in the church is something else!
你投靠本地帮  为虎作伥
You run with the Natives, pray with them!
你们会像你们的人一样被穿在桩子上
You're gonna wind up on a stake like your man did!
麦格罗恩
McGloin.
神父  天啊  你知道有个黑鬼跑到你的教堂里来了吗?
Father! Jesus, did you know there's a nigger in your church?
天啊
Jesus.
天翻地覆了
The earth turns
可我们并未觉察到
but we don 't feel it move.
直到某天晚上才突然发现
Then one night you look up.
星星之火  终于燎原
One spark, and the sky is on fire.
真是令人激动的场面
It's a touching spectacle.
你们准备好了我们会回来的
We'll come back when you're ready for us.
过去就是我们的指路明灯
The past is the torch that lights our way.
先辈们已经指引了我们该走的路  我们该追随其后
Where our fathers have shown us the path, we shall follow.
我们的信仰是敌人最惧怕的武器
Our faith is the weapon most feared by our enemies.
凭藉信仰我们可以激励同胞对抗欲置我们于死地的敌人
For thereby shall we lift our people up against those who would destroy us.
我们称自己为'死兔帮'  为了牢记我们过去经受的苦难
Our name is called the Dead Rabbits to remind all of our suffering
为了团结正在经受苦难的人们
and as a call to those who suffer still to join our ranks
团结那些从我们共同的家乡漂洋过海来到此地的人们
however so far they may have strayed from our common home across the sea.
因为众人同心  其利断金
For with great numbers must come great strength  and the salvation of our people.
- 你们那些事我们不想掺乎进来  - 有多少人住在这里?
- We don't want your business. - How many men live here?
- 都得来登记  - 你们不能强迫我入伍
- You all have to register. - You can't force me to join no army.
- 你有300美元吗?  - 当然没有
- Have you got $300? -  Of course not.
- 谁他妈的有300美元?  - 如果你被征召  想要免服兵役
- Who's got $300? - If you're drafted, release from service
需要缴纳300美元才行  这是征兵法规定的
can only be secured for $300, according to the Conscription Act.
- 否则  你就得入伍  - 谁他妈有300美元?
- Otherwise, you have to serve! - Who the hell's got $300?
你必须应征    除非你有300美元
You have to serve, sir, unless you have $300!
- 小伙子们  - 从哪来滚回哪去
- Boys! -  Go back to where you came from!
我在此土生土长  你是移民到此你就必须为这个国家战斗
I'm born in this country. You immigrated here. You will fight for this country!
天啊  战争真是可怕的灾难
Sweet Jesus! War does terrible things to men.
- 滚回富人区去  - 300美元?  又一场富人的战争
- Get back uptown where you belong! - $300? So it's another rich man's war.
先生  我想和此人谈谈
Sir, I request an audience with this man.
纽约已经没人说英语了吗?
No one speak English in New York anymore?
- 我不懂你说什么  - 原来你会说英语
- Don't understand. - You do speak English.
爱华亭小姐能否别把枪口这么对着我?
I wonder if Miss Everdeane could angle her rifle in some other direction.
瓦伦先生  不知道你是否明白这份宣传的真正价值
I wonder, Mr. Vallon, if you understand the true value of this sort of publicity.
大教主本人与五点区的半数爱尔兰人立场一致
The archbishop himself, shoulder to shoulder with the Irish in the Five Points.
我愿意与你们结盟对抗比尔·卡丁
I'm offering to form an alliance with you against Bill Cutting
及他支持的持本土论观点的候选人
and his slate of Nativist candidates.
我愿意出个很好的价钱给每位投票给坦慕尼的爱尔兰人
I'll negotiate a handsome fee for every Irish vote you send Tammany's way
在接下来的选举中
in the coming elections.
我需要在五点区物色一位新盟友
I need a new friend in the Five Points, son.
我希望这位朋友是你
I'd like that friend to be you.
等一下  特威德先生
Now, just a moment, Mr. Tweed.
如果你能拿到你希望的选票
Suppose we do get you those votes.
你能不能支持我选择的一位爱尔兰候选人?
Would you back an Irish candidate of my choosing?
- 恐怕不行  - 如果所有爱尔兰人都投你的票呢?
- I don't think so. - What if we get you all the Irish votes?
瓦伦先生  这简直是天方夜谭
That will only happen in the reign of Queen Dick.
- 你说什么?  - 就是永远不可能发生的事
- Beg your pardon? - It will never happen.
我倒是可以支持爱尔兰人竞选市议员
I might be persuaded to back an Irish candidate for, say, alderman.
- 市议员?  爱尔兰人已经有了市议员了
- Alderman? - We've already got Irish aldermen.
- 正因为如此  - 所以 比市议员大的是什么?
- So we have. That's why   - Well, what's bigger than alderman?
治安官  治安官  好了  特威德先生
Sheriff. Sheriff. All right, Mr. Tweed.
你支持一位爱尔兰人竞选纽约市或县的治安官
You back an Irishman for sheriff of the city and county of New York
我们会让他当选
and we'll get him elected.
我喜欢爱尔兰人  可高于市议员的职位你们永远不可能得到
I love the Irish, son, but higher than alderman you shall never climb.
- 为什么呢?  - 首先  没一个人
- Well, why not? - For one thing, no man living
- 能决定所有爱尔兰人的投票方向  - 我能
- can consolidate the Irish vote. -  I can.
其次  此话不怀恶意
And for another, I mean no effrontery
找不出一位爱尔兰人适合竞选治安官
no one's yet found an Irish candidate for sheriff worth voting for.
蒙克
Monk.
请看
Here.
看起来像我祖父一样镇定从容
He's to have me looking as sober as me own grandfather.
- 他肯定很了不起  - 他是个烂酒鬼
- Another great man, I'm sure. - A thorough drunken bastard.
我愿意试一试
Could I say what I want?
我正有此意
Well, that's why I wanted you.
我们选的代表们是一伙盗匪
Our elected representatives are a gang of thieves
赌咒发誓要为我们谋取更好的权益的同时
who swear to better our lot
手却伸到我们的腰包里去了
while dipping their hands deep into our pockets.
我与社区领袖们并肩作战比如这位比尔.卡丁先生
I stand shoulder to shoulder with community leaders like Bill Cutting
对抗所有敢于侵害民主的人
against any and all inroads into our fine democracy.
我要确保没人能夺走你们千辛万苦得来的东西
I'll see to it that no one takes away what you've earned by pluck and application.
入侵的爱尔兰蛮子
To invading hordes of Hibernians!
去把票投给沃尔特·麦克金
You go to the polls and you put your mark next to the name Walter McGinn.
打倒那帮吃土豆的比如那边那堆人  他们抢走了我们的饭碗
Against the potato eaters, like them over there, thieving our jobs!
为什么这么多爱尔兰人要到南方去送死?
Why should so many Irish die down south
我们的战场不是在南方各州  而是在这里的大街小巷里
when the first war to win is not down in Dixie, but right here in these streets?
谁是五点区最好的斗士?
And who's the finest street fighter in the Five Points?
- 蒙克  - 没错
- Monk! -  That's right.
那么让全城都听到你们的声音
Now, let the whole damn city hear it!
这人天生就是干这个的
That man was right born for this.
他杀过44人  打败的更有百人之多
Well, he's killed 44 men, laid low a couple hundred more.
- 是真的吗?  - 真的
- Is that right? - That's right.
我应该让他竞选市长
I should have run him for mayor.
好了  把他们全带走  今天是选举日
All right, line them up. It's election day!
快点  你们这些黄皮野种
Not so fast, you little yellow bastard!
起来
Come on!
起来  杂种  给我投票去
Come on, you bastard, we need your vote.
杂种？我过去为你们而战  黑鬼  还丢了条手臂
Bastard? I fought for you, nigger. I lost an arm for you.
还没算完  马上跟我走
Well, that's a start. Now, come on.
太阳出来了  太阳出来了
Rise and shine. Rise and shine.
我们这个伟大的国家里牛鬼蛇神也能投票
In this great country of ours, even the hop fiends get to vote!
别打扮了  加快动作
Less art and more haste, Don.
- 你去哪?  - 我今天已经投了票
- Where are you going? -  I already voted today.
投给了蒙克和坦慕尼  各两次
Cast for Monk and Tammany, by God. Twice.
两次?  才两次?  你就是这样行使公民权利的吗?  跟我来
Twice? Only twice? You call that doing your civic duty? Come with me.
你别走  回来坐下
Oh, no, you don't. Get back and sit down.
又一个  好好给他清理一下
Here's another one. Clean him up good.
把他们的胡子剃了  让他们再去投一次
Shave their beards and send them back to vote again.
好的  伙计们  投蒙克和坦慕尼  蒙克和坦慕尼
All right, boys. Vote Monk, Tammany. Monk, Tammany!
先生们  我们伟大的城市需要一座新法院
So, gentlemen, what our great city needs is a new courthouse.
我希望未来的法院应该比较经济节约
I propose it should be a modest, economical structure.
失陪一会  什么事?
Excuse me one moment.
蒙克已经比其他对手领先3000多票了
Monk's already won by 3000 more votes than there are voters.
这么少?  设法提高到2、3万去  我们不要小胜  我们要大捷
Three? Make it 20, 30. We don't need a victory. We need a Roman triumph!
- 我们没有多余的选票了  - 记住从政的首要准则
- But we don't have any more ballots. - Remember the first rule of politics:
选票不代表最后结果  最后的计票才代表结果  是计票
The ballots don't make the results, the counters make the results.
继续计吧
Keep counting.
本地美国人  请警惕境外势力
比尔送来的
It's from Bill.
蒙克
Monk.
今天  — 来自 比尔
五点区的公民们
Citizens of the Five Points
比尔.卡丁先生试图挑起纷争
Mr. Bill Cutting is attempting to draw me into an argument
最终无疑会引发流血事件进而危及我的办公室的安全
that would no doubt end in bloodshed and the compromising of my office.
大家什么看法?
What do you think?
我该选择按老规矩一言不发地应战
Should I engage in silence this relic of the ancient law?
还是选择在新的形势下  新的环境里作你们的代言人?
Or shall I be your chosen voice in a new testament, in the new world?
你看到了  比尔
There you are, Bill.
人们的态度已经表明了
The people have spoken.
长期的暴力纷争已经让人麻木了
The very notion of violent reprisal benumbs them.
上来吧
Come on up.
看我们能否以民主的方式解决纷争
Let's see if we can resolve our grievances the democratic way.
朋友  这是少数派的投票
That, my friends, is the minority vote.
知道我的厉害了吧  滋味如何?
Now you've tasted my mutton. How do you like it?
看着
Look.
我让你看看这里
I want you to see this.
这就是你  就在这
This is you. Right here.
第45条  你这个爱尔兰狗杂种
Notch 45, you Irish bog bastard.
你们把他烧了吧 看看他的骨灰会不会变成绿色
Why don't you burn him, see if his ashes turn green.
'命运眷顾勇者'
Fortune favors the bold!
- 你杀了选举出来的官员?  - 谁选了他?
- You killed an elected official? - Who elected him?
你不知道你干了些什么
You don't know what you've done to yourself.
我知道你的作风
I know your works.
你不冷也不热
You are neither cold nor hot.
因为你就是个冷血动物  我要呸在你身上
So because you are lukewarm, I will spew you out of my mouth.
你自己营造你的肮脏世界去吧
You can build your filthy world without me.
我干掉了父亲我还会干掉儿子
I took the father. Now I'll take the son.
你告诉小瓦伦我要用他的血油漆天堂广场
You tell young Vallon I'm gonna paint Paradise Square with his blood.
刷两层
Two coats.
我要用他的内脏装点我的卧室
I'll festoon my bedchamber with his guts.
至于你  操蛋坦慕尼.霍尔先生
As for you, Mr. Tammany-fucking-Hall
如果胆敢再踏入五点区
you come down to the Points again
我就会亲手宰了你
and you'll be dispatched by mine own hand.
回去参加你的庆典让我好好吃饭  老子给了你不少了
Now get back to your celebration and let me eat in peace. I paid you fair.
停
Stop.
起
Raise.
狗娘养的
You son of a bitch!
挑战
Challenge.
接受
Challenge accepted.
波多马克河部队第六军团
伤亡名单
美国历史上第一次联邦征兵
报名完毕
两万五千人将被调往纽约
七千人被调往布鲁克林区
终于来了  征兵的第一天
And then it came, the first day of the draft.
托马斯.内尔  安德鲁.路易斯  约瑟夫.弗林
Thomas O'Neill. Andrew Lewis. Joseph flynn.
他们念着被征召人的名字仿佛他们已经死了一样
They read out the draftees ' names like they was dead already.
安德鲁.马丁  J.B.克里森
Andrew Martin. J.B. Gleason.
- 奥康尔卫士帮  - 搅屎棍帮
- The O'Connell Guard. - The Plug Uglies.
- 我们这边  各帮派聚集在一起  - 四十大盗帮
- As for us, the tribes were gathered. - Forty Thieves.
- 齐切斯特帮  - 战鼓擂响
- The Chichesters. - The drums was beating.
死兔帮
The Dead Rabbits.
- 美国卫士帮  - 亚特兰蒂帮
- The American Guard. - The Atlantic Guard.
- 屠夫帮  - 鲍瑞小子
- The Slaughter Housers. - The Bowery Boys.
美洲本地人联帮
The Confederation of American Natives.
詹姆斯.穆尼
James Mooney.
可我们只看到一只手挡在我们面前
But all we could see was the hand in front of us.
肖恩.奥康耐尔
Sean O'Connell.
G.W.莫里斯  约翰.多洛
G.W. Morris. John Doyle.
- 时间?  - 你挑
- When? - Whenever you like.
- 明日黎明时分  - 地点?
- Daybreak tomorrow. - Ground?
天堂广场
Paradise Square.
武器?
Weapons?
- 你来决定吧  - 砖  棒  斧  刀
- That I leave up to you. - Bricks, bats, axes, knives
手枪?
Pistols?
不用手枪
No pistols.
好孩子
Good boy.
条件已谈好  会议结束
The terms are resolved. The council's concluded.
汤马斯.麦克维
Thomas McEvoy. W.H. Miles.
- 该死的征兵见鬼去吧  - 送他们下地狱
- To hell with your damned draft! - Give them hellfire, boys!
撕了他们
Rip them apart!
杀死有钱的王八蛋
Kill the rich bastards!
富人区
Uptown!
你们不能把我的儿子带走
You're not getting my son!
在富人区征兵处
Uptown at the draft office
警察打破了几个人的脑袋  众人四处逃散
the cops broke a few skulls, and everybody run away.
谣言四起
But the word was spreading
危机四伏
and the dark.
而在第五街
Up on Fifth Avenue
斯盖马洪家族和他的手下倒是神定气闲
the Schermerhorns and their mob breathed a little easy.
不过是发泄一下反对征兵的情绪
Just a brief burst of anger over Mr. Lincoln's draft.
我认为不是什么大问题
Entirely justifiable in my view.
- 这个问题有两个方面  格瑞里先生  - 任何问题都是多方面的
- There are two sides to that question   - There are several sides
可只有一面是正确的
but only one right side, as with any question
只要问题涉及到滥用行政职权
that involves the abuse of executive power.
无论如何  格瑞里先生
In any case, Mr. Greeley
我们应该庆幸情况没有恶化
we can all be thankful that it wasn't any worse.
已经恶化了  先生  我都看见了  我不知道怎么办
It may be worse yet. I saw them. I don't know what to think.
你常挂在嘴边的是哪句话?特威德先生?
Now what is it that you are so fond of saying, Mr. Tweed?
格瑞里先生  那句话你不喜欢  想起来了吗?
Mr. Greeley, you won't like this. But what is it?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
'你总是可以招募穷人的一半去杀掉另一半'
"You can always hire one half of the poor to kill the other half."
我来向你道别
I've come to say goodbye.
我已经订了去加利福尼亚的票
I've booked passage for California.
珍妮  给我一天时间  我会和你一起走
Jenny, give me one more day, and I'll go with you.
到那时你已经死了
You'll be dead by then.
- 那你要我怎么做?  - 我不知道
- Well, what would you have me do? - I don't know.
- 明天一切都会结束了  - 不会的
- This will all be finished tomorrow. - No, it won't.
不
No.
这个地方会陷入火海
This whole place is gonna burn anyway.
我听说穷人们在五点区正挨家挨户地
I've heard that the poor are going from door to door in the Five Points
要求那些希望继续闹事的人们
asking those supporters who wish to see further riots
在窗口点燃一枝蜡烛
to place a lighted candle in the window.
爱尔兰人  波兰人  德国人  所有的人
Irish, Poles, Germans, all of them.
格瑞里先生  城市不是疯了  我预言今夜漆黑一片
Mr. Greeley, the city is not mad. I prophesy a very dark night.
今天谁都不要上班  我们要关闭工厂
Nobody goes to work today! We'll shut the factories down!
第二天太阳升起的时候  整个城市分成了两半
When the sun rose next, the city had split in half.
人们从纽约各处赶来
From all over New York they came:
铁场工人  工厂职员  清洁工人
Ironworkers, factory boys, street cleaners
爱尔兰人  波兰人  德国人
Irish, Polish, German
从来没关心过奴隶制和联盟的人
anyone who never cared about slavery or the Union
所有没有钱支付免征兵的人
anyone who couldn 't buy his way out.
他们高喊'让富人的孩子去送死吧'
"Let the sons of the rich go and die, " they cried.
'让穷人的孩子留在家中'
"Let the sons of the poor stay home."
此刻天摇地动
The earth was shaking now.
而我则着手于父亲的事业
But I was about my father's business.
一群第五大街的败类
A bunch of fifth Avenue scums!
万能的主啊  你就是我手中的匕首
Almighty Lord, you are the dagger in my hand.
在此复仇之日导引我的手
Guide my hand on this day of vengeance.
我们感谢上帝的仁慈
We give thanks to the Lord, for he is good.
有你在  敌人插翅难逃
With you, the swift cannot flee, nor the strong escape.
让我的剑饱饮鲜血直到不再干渴
Let my sword devour until its thirst is quenched with blood
让我的敌人入土长眠
and my enemies sleep forever.
因为你是报应之主
For you are the Lord God of Retribution.
因为你是镇邪之主
For the Lord crushes the wicked.
因主充满慈悲
The Lord is merciful
祂的慈爱永远长存
and his love endures forever.
- 阿门  - 阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
阿门
Amen.
- 快走  狗娘养的  - 快出去
- Run away, you sons of bitches! - Come on out!
- 上楼  让女眷到楼上去  - 爸爸  爸爸
- Upstairs! Get the women upstairs! - Father! Father!
抓住这些畜生
Let's take the bastards!
18区  暴徒正在洗劫27街和第七大道住宅
From 18th Precinct: The mob are sacking houses, 27th Street and Seventh Ave.
我们已没有武力可派遣
We have no force to send.
16区  第八大道的所有商店都已关门
16th Precinct: All the stores are closing on Eighth Avenue
因为害怕十七街的暴徒
from fear of the mob in 17th Street.
看看你们有什么手段  胆小鬼
Show us what you got, you cowardly bastards!
第22街 18区
第四区  闹事者袭击了有色人种公寓
From 4th: The rioters are robbing colored boarding houses
洗劫一空后放火烧楼  21区
and setting them on fire. From 21st:
第3大街 和 第36街区
暴徒们冲入位于3大道的一家枪械店
The mob have just broken open gun store and are arming.
第27街区 和 第7大街
- 抓住黑鬼  -杀了他  - 拆了坦慕尼家！
- Get the nigger! Kill him! - Tear Tammany down!
位于3大道的美国警署正在燃烧  警察束手无策
The marshal's office is burning down. The police is of no avail.
出来  特威德
Show yourself, Tweed!
两位有色人种濒临死亡
Two colored men brought in almost dead.
马布里街警察总署
有50多位黑人需要救援  黑人四处被袭击
There are more Negroes who need help. They're being attacked all over.
那有个富家子弟  抓住他
Hey! There's a $300 man. Get him!
你老爸花钱让你不用参军?  他能帮我出这个钱吗?
Did your daddy buy you out of the Army? Can he buy me out too?
华尔街和沃特街
位于21街二大道的军火库有被暴徒袭击的危险
There's danger of mob attacking armory, corner 21st Street, Second Avenue.
里面约有500件武器
There is about 500 stand of arms in it.
线路断了  暴徒正在破坏所有的线路
The line is dead! They're trying to cut all the wires!
1区  暴徒们聚集在北河4码头  他们杀死了那里的黑人
From 1st: Riot at Pier 4, North River. They have killed Negroes.
一群人正准备摧毁整个港口
A crowd is here and are going to destroy this station.
抢她的包  抢她的包
Get her bag! Get her bag!
勒星顿大街和46街区
18区
From 18th Precinct:
暴徒袭击了军械库  大楼有着火的危险
The mob have attacked the armory. There is danger of firing the building.
所有三百名警察都已受伤或下落不明
All 300 police wounded or unaccounted for.
请寻找军队并派至
Find the military and send them
20街  派遣100个人驱散攻击市长住处的歹徒
From 20th: Send 100 men to disperse mob assailing Mayor Opdyke's house.
2大道33街的建筑物被暴徒焚烧
Building corner 33rd Street Second Avenue, set on fire by the mob.
巴纳姆博物馆  百老汇
巴纳姆博物馆正在起火  动物正在逃生
Barnum 's American Muzeum on fire. Animals are escaping.
放手！
Let go! Let go!
让这婊子别叫唤了  按住她
Hush the shickster! Hold her down!
'自由号'及'帕萨克号'停泊在华尔街附近
Gunboat Liberty and ironclad Passaic now lying off the foot of Wall Street.
他们已准备好向暴徒开火
They are ready to open fire on the mob.
大批暴徒正前往5大道  准备袭击论坛报大厦
Lynch mob, now going down Fifth Avenue, to attack Tribune office.
论坛报大厦  公园街
16区  暴徒正前往火车站   我们已无人手
From 16th: Mob 's coming down to station. We have no men.
- 18区- 暴徒非常凶猛  - 16区  军队已经抵达
- 18th: The mob is very wild. - From 16th: 7th Regiment has arrived.
正从运河街赶往百老汇
Foot of Canal, they are on their way to Broadway.
拿开你的手
Take your hands off me!
暴徒大约有4500人
The mob is about 4500 strong.
他们要焚烧哈莱姆大桥  哈莱姆大桥已被点燃
They're going to burn down Harlem Bridge. Harlem Bridge is to be torched.
- 格瑞里先生  - 鼠辈们占领了城市
- Mr. Greeley! -  The rats have taken over the city!
第8大街  32街区附近
21区  发生一起袭击有色人种事件
From 21st: There is an attack on the colored people in Second Avenue
有一名暴徒前往有色人种孤儿院  派军队去保护孩子
Mob headed for the Colored Orphans Asylum. Protect the children!
7大道28街发生暴乱
Rioters on Seventh Avenue, 28th Street.
中心街和富兰克林街
- 他们刚杀了一名黑人  - 抓住他
- They have killed a Negro. - Get him!
长官  少将想知道如何处理犯人
Sir, the Major General wants to know what to do with any prisoners captured
犯人?  别管犯人了  暴徒不会对付犯人
Prisoners? Don't take any. The mob isn't taking prisoners!
平息暴乱前别抓犯人
Put the mob down! Don't take a prisoner in until you've put the mob down!
军队在38街  暴徒不肯散去
Soldiers now on 38th Street. The mob will not disperse.
请你快下命令  请你快下命令
What are your orders? What are your orders?
五点区
- 不征兵  不征兵  - 让他们知道我们对征兵的看法
- No draft! No draft! - Show them what we think of their draft!
皮特街和布鲁姆街
- 站在一起  - 好的
- Stick together! - All right.
立定!
Troop, halt!
出枪!
Present arms!
我依约前来  瓦伦
On your order, Vallon.
坚持 坚持住
Hold fast, there. Hold fast, there.
我命令你们立即疏散
I order you to disperse!
开枪
Fire!
右舷开火
Fire starboard!
右舷猛攻  开火!
Starboard battery, fire!
快走
Come on, let's go!
往他们头上开火
Fire over their heads!
把他们赶进广场
Drive them into the square!
比尔
Bill!
开火
Fire!
前进
Advance!
比尔
Bill!
我不能走路了
I can't walk!
起来
Get up!
开火
Fire!
- 畜生！  - 尚!  尚!  别过去
- Bastards! - Shang! Shang, hold off!
感谢上帝
Thank God.
我作为真正的美国人而死
I die a true American.
明天早上  我们的人全得到码头去
Tomorrow morning, get our people down to the docks.
我要每个下船的人们都能拿到热汤和面包
I want every man and woman coming off the boats given hot soup and bread.
今晚我们在这里埋掉不少选票
We're burying a lot of votes down here tonight.
最后  人们在尸体上点燃蜡烛  这样他们的朋友
In the end, they put candles on the bodies so 's their friends
如果他们有朋友的话  在黑暗中能认出他们来
if they had any, could know them in the dark.
这是市府免费提供的
The city did this free of charge.
尚  吉米.斯波尔斯  地狱猫  麦格罗恩  还有更多人
Shang, Jimmy Spoils, Hell-Cat, McGloin and more.
敌或友  现在已没有了区别
Friend or foe, it didn 't make no difference now.
经过了四个昼夜  暴动终于得以平息
It was four days and nights before the worst of the mob was finally put down.
期间多少纽约人命丧黄泉永远不可得知
We never knew how many New Yorkers died that week
在城市重获新生之前
before the city was finally delivered.
父亲说我们都诞于苦难与鲜血之中
My father told me we was all born of blood and tribulation.
我们伟大的城市也是如此
And so then too was our great city.
那些激情燃烧的岁月里的生死恩怨
But for those of us what lived and died in them furious days
正如我们所熟悉的一切终成过眼云烟
it was like everything we knew was mightily swept away.
重建城市的人们  不管付出多少血泪
And no matter what they did to build the city up again
威廉·卡丁（1863）     牧师瓦伦（1801-1846）
随着时光流逝
for the rest of time
终如春梦一般  了却无痕
it would be like no one even knew we was ever here.
纽约黑帮